Okay, we can start preparing now.
Hello everyone, I'm Sherry from Marvelous Designer.
Today we are very honored to invite Ada, or Annie Radon, to our live broadcast as a guest.
Please, Ada, let's start.
Thank you for inviting me, Sherry.
It's my second time doing an official live broadcast on MD.
This time, I'm going to talk about something related to topology.
Many of you use MD in the digital entertainment industry, right?
So, for example, if you want to make a game model or a movie model, you can't use the MD model directly.
We need to make a re-topology for it.
So this time, I'm going to talk about the re-topology in a systematic way.
And then I'll start talking.
Okay.
Because in fact, the content of MD Topology is actually seen a lot on the Internet, including Bilibili and YouTube.
In fact, you can find a lot of teaching related to MD Topology on this website.
But I've always felt that there's a problem.
That is, the teaching of these operations is not very systematic.
That is, it is not well-arranged.
Many are very fragmented.
So this time, what I'm talking about is going to be a little systematic.
I'm going to give you an overview of all kinds of types and all kinds of situations, so that it's convenient for everyone to understand this thing in just one lecture.
Of course, the content will be relatively dry, it will be relatively dry, it may be relatively boring, it may be relatively boring.
And then if you think it's okay, actually, I can put a bgm like this, it might be a little better.
Otherwise, I'm sure I'll see half of it and fall asleep.
Is that okay? Can I put a bgm that's a little easier?
Like this
Then I'll just put it like this.
There are broadcasts, there are broadcasts, there are broadcasts.
Okay, let's go down.
And then this is my personal introduction.
Last time, when I was talking about it last time, I had done a personal introduction.
So this time I'm not going to talk about it.
Anyway, my real name is Wu Hongbin.
And then I'm an ordinary three-dimensional.
And then my bgm main page is just to type in Andy Ryden.
That's the name.
And then you can find me on Bilibili.
It's an ordinary three-dimensional.
And then this.
And then this time we're going to talk about this.
Wait a minute.
Before I finish this, I'm going to make an advertisement first.
To change the music.
Then this MD official is now in cooperation with CG model network.
A MD Chinese official course.
Marvelous Designer.
A course like this.
This course is now available on CG model network official.
You can buy it after you enter the first page.
And then in the tutorial here.
And then click on this tutorial.
Or you can click on Marvelous Designer here in the tutorial.
You can see this page.
And then this is a video tutorial.
And then it's not just a tutorial.
It also provides a month.
A month of Marvelous Designer.
This is the license for use.
License for use.
Then.
And then it's a course.
There's one.
This is the case you see.
And then there's also this software contact operation.
And then it's our Sherry.
Our Sherry.
To give a very good video tutorial.
Okay.
And then the video is a total of six hours and fifty-three minutes.
This is one of them.
And then another advertisement.
It's me.
I also started an MD course in Marvelous CG.
And then.
From here you can click in.
And then there are three live broadcasts every week.
Tuesday, Thursday, Saturday.
Three live broadcasts.
Take you to do some cases.
And then it will last for about two months.
And then.
These two courses are more than 200 yuan.
If you are interested, you can take a look.
In addition to this.
In Marvelous Designer.
There is now an official competition event.
There is a competition event.
It's called Laird Studio and Marvelous Designer.
Marvelous Designer.
It's Adobe's collaboration.
They did a three-dimensional competition together.
This competition.
I think it's going to last a long time.
And then.
There is a theme every month.
A prize will be awarded every month.
And then.
Including Sherry.
She is also in this as a judge.
And then.
This.
There are so many kinds of awards.
There are so many things at first place.
I want so many things in second place.
There are so many things at third place.
It's also in the registration now.
If you want to sign up.
You can visit the official website of Marvelous Designer in the news page.
Then there is an activity page after click the Pick Up page.
It has amazing things.
You can enter the event direct discor for details.
Today's official program up here.
Okay, let's switch back to the music.
Okay, let's start today's content.
This time, we will mainly talk about重拓譜.
Before talking about重拓譜, we all say that the concept of重拓譜 is actually重拓譜.
So, what exactly is a重拓譜?
First of all, let's talk about what a重拓譜 is.
What is the purpose of a重拓譜?
Here, I have opened Maya.
That's right, it's not Blender, it's Maya.
Is my voice a little too loud?
I'll move my microphone a little further away.
I'll turn down the volume a little bit.
Hello, hello, hello, hello, hello.
Okay, the volume is a little bit lower.
Okay, let's take a look.
I think my voice is a little too loud.
Let's take a look.
There are four balls on the surface of this Maya, right?
Four balls.
So these four balls are all in the shape of a ball.
It looks almost the same.
Except for the last one, the number of faces may be a little less.
In other words, it actually looks like the number of faces is almost the same.
So in the three-dimensional world, our...
Ah?
The sound has become lower just now, right?
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Then I'll turn the volume up a little bit.
Okay.
Is this sound okay?
Maya is not a Maya person.
What are you talking about?
Okay.
Then let's take a look.
So first of all, these four balls are in the three-dimensional world.
We need to use the point line to form a volume.
In this way, it can form a three-dimensional model.
So how to arrange our point line on the surface of a volume?
This is what we call top.
Top.
Top is a concept like this.
Then we can see these four balls.
The arrangement of the point line surface of these four balls is completely different.
It's completely different.
But they can all describe or describe such a ball size.
So this represents this arrangement.
This arrangement is called a three-dimensional model of a top structure.
A three-dimensional model of a top structure.
So if...
For example, a ball of this shape.
Then for example, I want to do animation.
Or I need to do dynamic analysis.
Or for example, I want to do deformation.
Then there are some top structures.
For example, a top structure like this.
It may not be suitable for me to do deformation.
When doing deformation.
Because some of its arrangement problems will lead to.
For example, the entire model will be twisted and deformed.
Right?
For example, I have a model with a very high aspect ratio.
But I want to make it a game model.
But the game requires higher performance.
That is to say, if the model has a very high aspect ratio.
I can't run the game.
Right?
Because the game needs to run 60 frames per second.
Now there are even 120 frames and 144 frames of games.
Then the cost of this rendering is very high.
The cost of performance is very high.
So if the aspect ratio is very high.
It does not support our computer to run such high frames.
So we need to reduce its aspect ratio.
So all kinds of needs.
That's why we need to change this object again.
The top structure on the surface.
Such a process is called re-top.
It's called re-top.
Wait a minute.
What are you talking about?
OK.
This concept is called the concept of re-top.
It's called the concept of re-top.
Then put this concept in our Marvelous Designer.
That is to say, the clothes we made in Marvelous Designer.
It is also a three-dimensional model in essence.
Right?
Then such a three-dimensional model.
It has all kinds of this kind of top solution.
There are all kinds of top solutions in the software.
Then let's make a simple case first.
Then let's take a look at what kind of solutions it has.
The content of today's video is very original.
If you already know how to operate it,
You can, for example,
Just as a consolidation.
Then we opened MD10 here.
Marvelous Designer 10.
Then here,
We can make a simple T-shirt mountain.
Make a T-shirt mountain.
It's very simple.
We can first aim at its screen.
We can aim at its screen.
Then we.
For example, we draw one here.
This is half of its front.
OK.
Then let's give it, for example,
Add a point.
Then here, too.
For example, add a point.
Then we use this moving tool.
Let's make a simple one.
Let's make a simple T-shirt.
This upper body.
Let's make it a little bit longer.
A little bit wider.
OK.
Then we're here.
Give it.
Make one.
Like this.
It's almost like this.
Then pull down a little bit here.
OK.
Then we.
For example,
Open it with symmetry here.
Then we make another sleeve.
This is its front.
Right?
Then we can, for example,
Ctrl C, Ctrl V.
In this way.
This is its back.
Then we pull it over.
Pull it over.
Then we turn it over.
The shortcut is Ctrl G.
Then.
In this way.
It has a back.
Of course, the back.
This may be a little bit too low.
Let's make it a little bit higher.
Then we use the curve tool.
Make it a little bit.
In this way.
We probably have the feeling of the front and the back.
It's made.
Although the sleeve is a little bit small.
So if you want to make it bigger.
You can make it a little bit bigger.
And then use the curve tool.
Make it a little bit bigger.
Actually, you don't have to change it.
We'll just show you today.
Right?
And then we'll draw another sleeve.
So what about the sleeves?
Many people may think that the sleeves are not very easy to draw.
So I can introduce a very, very simple.
Silly.
And the correct way to draw sleeves.
Then we use a square.
Let's align it first.
Draw a square.
You do this.
Align it.
Draw a square.
Then.
You face it.
This.
Angle.
Then you draw a curve point.
For example.
Here.
Wait a minute.
We need to make it a little bit oblique.
Then.
We face it.
This angle.
We draw a curve point.
Then.
Then let's pull it in.
Ah.
So let's try to keep it in.
Keep this in.
But.
You shift Z.
You'll see that the size is different.
Right?
And then we'll just click right here.
Right.
And then.
This side has a change in length.
We'll just enter the length on the right side.
Is ok.
Seventeen points.
33.
Then?
You can change it.
Which point is the extension?
I want the following point to be extended.
So it's the same length.
Right?
After the length is the same.
Isn't it just a sleeve?
And then.
This is the whole sleeve, isn't it?
But there is a small problem here
We found that this curve point is not too good
Then we go ahead and adjust it a little bit
Just adjust it
That's about it
And then 17.46 is a little bit over
And then the length is changed
For example, 17.33 is actually a little bit worse
It doesn't matter
Especially if the sleeve is a little bit higher
His sleeves will be a little stiffer
Let's not talk about this
We're not making clothes today
OK
And then this is a sleeve
After you open it like this
This sleeve will ensure that the size of your sleeve and the size of your clothes is completely consistent
It's completely accurate
And then your sleeves are also symmetrical
This is completely correct
Including when you sew
Because it's divided into two sections
So it's very easy to sew
This is a little trick of mine
And then this can be a little bit longer
And then what about this
We can just sew it on top of this
And then the first one is copied to a sleeve
And then put this here
OK, and then we can sew it directly here
We can sew it in the three-dimensional interface
Because we have a mirror
So, actually, as long as you sew it on one side
He'll sew it on for you on the other side
Including this place
You see, I'm a little bit like this
Is it sewn up here
And then this side is also here
Is it sewn up
And then we can press the control button on the spot
And then let him do this
And then we sew the two ends of the sleeve together
Press the control button
A shirt
A very simple T-shirt shirt
Is it done
But this T-shirt shirt is a little bit rough
We can take a look at it later
Where did you get it wrong
First of all, this shirt is too short
This is a deer suit
Let's make it a little bit longer
Take a look at it
It's still a good fit
And then the normal sleeves
He's actually a little bit thinner
So we're using this tool here
This tool doesn't have a shortcut
I can't click
There's something on it that's blocking me
That's his
Tencent's live broadcast software
You choose
And then the point in the middle of the double-click
You can do this to collect it
This still ensures that your object is symmetrical
And then
Take a look
OK
Well, that's more than perfect
And then you can press this out button
Take a look at this pressure chart
You'll find that this is the position of the sleeve
And it's a little tight like this
But today because we're not making clothes
We're just going to show you a little bit of the top
So this is the part of the clothes
It's just for me to take my time
So it doesn't matter
We don't have to care about him anymore
And then we can do the sleeve
You can also do the collar or something like that
I'll take a look at the time
I can still do it if I'm allowed
So we can do one
For example, let's extend this a little bit
Let's extend this a little bit
How to do the sleeve
It's actually very simple
You choose these two points
And then you click on the internal line
And then you choose one
For example, the sleeve
Usually we set a sleeve that is about three to four centimeters
We're just about three centimeters
And then the internal line is extended
So that it extends to both sides
If you don't click
It's empty
You click it
And then confirm it again
And then at this point
You click on the cut and sew
And then you choose this double machine
And then shorten it a little bit
In this case
We just need a sleeve
And then you can shrink it a little bit
For example, that kind of thing
It's like that kind of shrink cloth
What kind of loose cloth
Here you can take a look at this
The effect of our sleeve is coming out
Right
So the same way
We can do the same effect on the bottom of our clothes
But I think that's about it
And then the collar
We can also use a similar method
We can make a collar
But I'll take a look at the time
It's about time
What's going on
Is the timing too fast
OK
All right
Let's go on
And then that's about it
Right
And then we can go to him
When it's time to settle
Give him a drag
So that he has more details
There are more details
If you want that kind of soft cloth
In fact, here is a recommendation
First of all
Because of your
If you don't have enough face
Shift Z
Turn off this display
If you don't have enough face
In fact, you should go
What about his wrinkle?
It's not good
So first of all
Let's make the face
Make the face a little higher
So that he can do it
It will become more detailed
The other one
It's our fabric preset
You can choose one
For example
Like we sometimes do
The nylon featherweight used for the down jacket
This is the one that's on the outside of the down jacket
The effect of the very thin fabric
The effect of the nylon
The effect of the light nylon
This is very suitable
For example
Our T-shirt
Let's simulate its effect
You can see
This effect will come out right away
Right
And then
Including
You can also use expansion and contraction
To go further
For your clothes
To add some details
Hey, let's pull some of this sleeve's wrinkles out
How beautiful is it?
So MD's new version
It also has a GPU resolution function
So GPU resolution
He will have some problems with self-contact
But in our case
There is no self-contact
If we open the GPU resolution
His speed will skyrocket
You can see
It suddenly becomes so fast
Is it very useful
Just to say
It will self-contact
Yes
There are still some
There are some small problems
There are still some small problems
You can see
It's self-contact here
Right
So in general
Like this kind of high-resolution
We can adjust it first
After that
Let's go back to this ordinary CPU
And then we run it again
Basically, it can solve the problem
I can't even tell if he's running it
OK
Well, that's it
Our clothes
This simple one is fine
A small demonstration of our clothes is done
You can see MD making clothes is very, very, very convenient
Very fast
You can also make a lot of details
You want to carve it in ZB
Can carve you to death
Right
Like me
I might have to carve two or three hours
I can carve it like this
Right
If you're not familiar
You can't carve it for a day
And then we can continue to go down now
Display its top structure
So first of all
Let's take a look at what MD offers
Where is the playback 0.5x speed adjusted
Don't worry
And then let's take a look at what top is in MD
First of all, we can open this frame display on the fabric side
We can see
Let's open this one
It's pretty clear
You can see that MD is default
It's this triangular shape
Why is it this shape
Because this is about this kind of multidirectional resolution
Multidirectional resolution
In fact, you can understand it as everything particle
Everything particle
So all of these
All of these points
It's actually his main solution
This is the main collision
It's all about solving these points
So these lines are actually the relationship between points and points
So he so he will form a kind of this kind of network structure based on the triangular surface
In this case
It's more conducive to his kind of fabric resolution
It's probably you can probably understand it that way
The actual principle is not like this
This is just to make it easier for you to understand
So I'm telling you
So in this triangular shape
Its operation
Including his real-time
For example, if you drag these fabrics
He he will change
Right
So these real-time cloth lines will change
So when these cloth lines change
This kind of triangular surface is the easiest to calculate
The calculation speed is the fastest
So he's in this default situation
It's all like this
So this kind of triangular surface
In fact, it's not good for us to do all kinds of other processes
But direct rendering is no problem
Direct rendering is still good
So let's go over here
Let me see if we have time
If we don't have time, forget it
Forget it if we don't have time
Then we won't show it
That is to say
If we just import it
For example, like Cloud 3D
Or like Blender
Or software like Maya
You have this triangular surface
If you turn it into a soft edge
Forget it
Let me show you this
Let's export OBJ here
And then we're here
Select this is our high-end model
And then this is 02
And then this is what I tested before
Yeah, I've been running this lecture a lot of times before
And then we turn off the virtual model
One target
And then thin
And then unify the UV coordinates
Unite
And then limit
Confirm after no problem
And then in that case
We're going to export this model
After exporting
We can open our software
Blender Blender
And then we're in Blender
We can directly
Insert our OBJ file
And then I'll take a look at this one
The file is on the desktop
Then MD official live retopo
And then the high-end model we just did
And then here are a few data
Save the top order
Multilinear group
Insert OBJ
If that's the case
We're going to import this model
And then we're going to click on the delete on the keyboard
Just the delete key on the small keyboard
Let it center
Or if you have an M3 plug-in
You just click the F key
And you can center it
So you can see this model coming in
And then if you think this model is coming in
If you think this model is coming in
If there is something wrong, you can press A to select all, then SHIFT N to let it recalculate the hair line outwards.
In this way, there is basically no problem.
Then we can look at the direction of the object here and then automatically smooth it.
Click on the right button and then give it a smooth color.
In this way, there is no problem.
Then you can see that the actual effect of this rendering can be used as one of our effects.
As long as you don't move it, you don't let it move.
In fact, you can directly render it.
We don't have a light here, just give it a light.
SHIFT A and then we just make a light here.
Then we put the light, for example, in this position.
Then we add a plane in SHIFT A.
Then press S to enlarge it.
Then press G and Z to put it up.
It looks good in the shadow.
Then we press Z and then we can use rendering here.
We can see it or not.
Then we can enlarge its brightness here.
Hmm.
Is it darkness?
Hierarchy is set to this.
Well.
It's this dark.
Then we set up the second?
You can see it.
consecrated too ac wed
Actually, it's pretty good.
There's nothing wrong with it.
Nothing wrong with it is as big as a word.
Which means that in fact three-sided interpreters, as a our one,
There's no problem with his encrypted word.
You can totally use it.
But once you j Pizza it, you're done.
Because it's all on three sides.
Then we do this first.
Maybe you don't know much about this triangle part.
I can also introduce it a little bit more simply.
For example, let's go back to Maya.
So, for example,
Let's make it simple here.
Let me show you.
For example, this is a death face, right?
And then we copy one.
For example, this one.
Let's make it a triangle.
The number of faces is a little high.
Maybe you can't see it very clearly.
Let me re-create it.
Let's give one.
What?
For example, let's give it a little less number of faces.
For example, give five and five.
OK, then let's copy another one.
I'll turn off the Blender.
Otherwise, it keeps running.
My computer is spinning and saving.
For example, like this.
Two models.
So one is a four-sided face.
Let's give him a triangle.
So this side is for you.
For everyone.
Let me show you.
Oh, my God.
I'm blocked up here.
I can't see it.
For example, let's add a transformer for him.
This curved transformer.
And then we're going to adjust the range of this transformer.
And then we're going to, for example, press this button.
Let's turn it around a little bit like this.
So here, too, we're going to give him a curve transformer.
And then we're going to turn it around like this.
So we're going to...
Okay, so this is the four-sided side.
Let's press three.
This triangle.
This may not be too obvious.
Let's turn it over and have a look.
And then we're going to give him a sewing material.
Okay.
And then we're going to put the same sewing material on top of this.
Do you see the difference?
It's very smooth.
But what about this?
You can see it.
It's a little weird.
A turn.
Right.
This is because there's something on the triangle.
This thing.
This thing is called torii, called torii.
It's called torii.
You can use...
I can't get it.
It's on top.
How do I put this together?
It's done.
What?
I can't get it.
I have a Tencent meeting on it.
I'm here.
How familiar is Windows to use
And then this one, for example, we are PORE.
It's called a point or a new point.
So the new point usually has three new points and five new points.
So in our production
As long as you have a triangle, there will be three new points or five new points.
So this one is very influential.
Our kind of transformation operation
Transformation operation
You have a model like this.
How do you divide it?
It's all a mess.
So what about a model like this?
No matter how many times you divide it, it's extremely smooth.
This is the difference between the four-sided and the triangle model.
It's mainly based on this point.
So like what we saw in MD just now.
What about a model like that?
It's wrong.
So in this MD
The model we see here is all three-sided.
So we can't use it for animation.
You can't use it for animation.
What about animation?
It's a transformation.
And then there's a lot of stuff on your body.
It's all out of control.
Unless you have a very, very, very, very high face.
But if you have a very, very, very high face.
It's actually not convenient to do animation.
It's going to be stuck, right?
OK, and then this is something related to the triangle.
That's why you don't use the triangle.
So except for the triangle.
There's another model in MD.
It's a four-sided.
So what about this four-sided?
You just need to right-click on it.
And then I'm going to click on the square here.
So it's going to turn into a four-sided.
Just a little bit here.
Because the number of faces is relatively high.
Oh, my God.
Shouldn't I be using such a high number of faces?
It's a little bit.
Oh, no.
OK, so now we're going to go into the four-sided.
The four-sided is the square.
This is the four-sided of MD.
But you'll find that the four-sided of MD is like this.
It's like this.
It's still not usable.
Why?
You look closely.
Is there a lot of this new point on it?
OK.
This weird triangle.
Right?
Five-star point.
I see five-star points.
Five-star points.
There are three-star points everywhere.
So what about this model?
If you go into detail.
It's going to have a lot of
There's still nothing to do about it.
And there's no way to carve it.
In fact, you can actually show it here.
Just put it in this brush.
But I don't have enough time.
Because I'm probably going to talk about an hour or so.
So there's more to the back of the operation.
So I'll try to talk a little bit faster.
So you can see that it has a lot of these new points.
This model.
You can see that it has a lot of these new points.
There's still nothing to do about it.
What do we need to use in the film or game high mode?
It's a model that doesn't show horizontal values.
Horizontal values of this model.
For example, like this.
Horizontal values.
So MD.
The official gave us another model.
That's what we're doing here.
If you click right here.
I'm going to make this a little bit higher.
Don't make it so low.
For example, like this.
And then we'll go to the right.
And then we choose.
There's a kind of reset grid here.
Reset grid is MD.
In which version is it?
The version of 9 or 8.
A newly added grid format.
This grid format.
Oh, my God.
It's very neat, isn't it?
That's what we want.
But there's a problem.
Its interface.
Its edge is like this.
So in fact.
If you're willing to fix it.
In fact, you can.
Fix it little by little.
And then fix it to normal.
The model we're using.
But actually.
For us.
It's still not very useful.
One is that its face is too high.
If the face is too low.
It's actually better for us to do it manually.
Right?
And then there's that.
Sometimes it's this.
This operation.
It's actually his face.
It's hard to get it right.
Maybe it's harder to get it right.
Because his parameters may be completely different.
And then you need to spend a long time to get it right.
This model.
But this model.
That's what we just saw.
That one.
The three-sided.
The four-sided model.
We can use it to directly render.
We can use it to go back to the model directly.
No problem.
But you can't do animation.
So this kind of model.
It's very suitable.
Use it to do.
Dissolution agent model.
What is the dissolution agent model?
For example.
We're in.
We're in Maya.
For example.
If we're going to make a dress.
We may or may not say.
A piece of cloth.
A piece of clothing.
We're just like this.
Right?
I might.
For example.
My edge is.
The edge is going to do that.
For example.
Curving.
Right?
I might go in again.
I might want to do one of these.
Curving.
Right?
And then.
Go up again.
Something like this.
Right?
I might.
For example.
Which edge.
And then.
For example.
I'm going to do one.
I'm going to do one of those.
What?
Just show it.
For example.
We're going to do one.
Something like this.
And then.
Maybe.
We're going to do one.
What?
What am I doing?
For example.
I'm going to do a squeeze effect.
What?
I'll just do it.
Like this.
For example.
A piece of cloth.
There are all kinds of details on it.
Of course.
This is a little weird.
I'll just show it to you.
For example.
A piece of cloth.
We might do all kinds of details on it.
Then.
A model like this.
You're in Maya.
Or in Blender.
Or in Max.
You can't just use this to solve it.
Right?
Because.
If you solve it.
It's based on your every point.
To solve it.
So.
If you just go ahead and solve it.
It's going to be a problem.
That includes.
It's the same in MD.
If your MD model.
Put it in Maya.
Or something like that.
You've done all kinds of details on it.
I've done a lot of things.
For example.
The zipper.
Something like that.
All kinds of things on it.
For example.
The button.
The pocket.
What?
All kinds of things.
It's on it.
Including some decorations.
Right?
Yeah.
And then.
Like embroidery.
Something like that.
Then.
You can't.
No way.
There's no way.
To take it.
It's going to be solved directly.
So what do you do at this point?
So you can take it.
The original model in MD.
That's what we just did.
This model.
You can use it.
Rewriting the grid.
This is the original model.
To solve it.
After solving it.
Use it.
To wrap it up.
We're in Maya.
Sit on it.
Or in Blender.
The object with the details.
So that the object.
It can present.
This kind of uniform.
The movement of the fabric.
This is one.
When we're doing special effects.
When it comes to character special effects.
When it comes to fabric.
Will be used.
One.
Method.
Then this kind of.
Rewriting the grid.
This model.
It's very suitable.
Used to do.
Calculation.
Administrative model.
Because it's.
Enough.
Even.
Ah.
Enough.
Even.
But because of his.
The problem with this interface.
So it's not suitable for us.
To do.
This kind of.
It's not suitable for us.
To do.
This kind of.
It's carving.
Or something like that.
These jobs.
Because he.
His edge.
The number.
It's a lot worse.
So there's no way.
OK.
And then.
Ah.
This is.
Let me see.
My PPT.
OK.
So these are.
It's all.
It's a one-off.
In our MD.
Ah.
All-automatic.
One-off.
Three ways.
So the last one.
The way.
It's our MD.
He's actually.
It's built-in.
Top tools.
So it's in.
This new version.
9.
Added.
Top tools.
And then.
Including.
It's 10.
And then.
11.
It's optimized.
A lot of things.
So we can.
Take a look.
MD.
Inside.
Give us.
A solution.
So we're here.
Will use.
MD.
11.
To.
To demonstrate.
Why.
I didn't use MD.
11.
Because.
MD.
11.
A little.
Card.
So.
If.
It's.
So fast.
To do.
Then.
MD.
11.
He can't keep up.
My speed.
It's so.
Strong.
Hey.
Go.
Eight.
The.
Snow.
It's eight.
It's okay.
I don't know.
I didn't see it.
I'm going back.
Okay.
I'm back.
And then.
Let's go back to this.
Clothes.
And then.
Let's take this file.
Save it.
And then.
Let's save it here.
MD.
The files can be opened to each other.
That is to say.
You.
High version.
You can also.
The floor version.
You can also open the high version of the file.
The high version.
You can also open the floor version of the file.
And then.
Claw.
3D.
And the software of Marvelous Designer.
Is.
That file.
It's interactive.
This is very good.
This.
Next door.
Substance.
You take a look.
Okay.
Let's open this.
And then.
Just click.
OK.
Then.
We can.
In 11.
Put the clothes that were made just now.
It's poured in.
It's very convenient.
Right.
Okay.
And then.
Here.
It provides.
The built-in.
This.
Top solution.
Is this.
Tool.
Then.
It has.
Editing.
Top.
Creative.
And.
Intellectual.
Top.
Three functions.
Then.
We.
Here.
Let's take a look.
That's.
First.
It has.
Creative.
Top.
You.
After you click.
Directly.
Enter.
Into.
A.
Top.
The interface.
Inside.
Came.
Then.
You.
Just.
What do you do.
Up there.
That's right.
Draw points.
And then.
You.
As long as.
It's closed.
Hey.
It's just.
That's it.
Hey.
You can draw one by one.
Very happy.
OK.
That's it.
Then.
I can.
6 hours in a row.
It's all this.
That's it.
And then.
You can.
A little bit.
Finish drawing this object.
After you're done.
You can.
Right click.
And then.
You can.
Give it.
Do that.
Dividing.
Just.
If you.
Use this.
Editing.
Top.
Tool.
And then.
You.
Click on the top.
Right click.
And then.
You can.
Go.
Give.
It.
Do.
Increase.
Dividing.
And then.
It.
Will.
Have.
More.
Faces.
But.
Except.
These.
In addition.
It.
There.
Is.
Its.
Function.
More.
Original.
Then.
He.
Later.
It.
Also.
Launched.
A.
Intelligent.
Top.
Tool.
This.
Is.
More.
Powerful.
This.
More.
Powerful.
Then.
Let's.
Take.
This.
Shoe.
To.
Do.
A.
Demonstration.
For example.
I.
Want.
To.
Do.
A.
Shoe.
Piece.
In.
The.
Middle.
This.
Piece.
For example.
I.
Want.
To.
Do.
This.
Side.
Of.
This.
Piece.
Then.
For example.
I.
Want.
Horizontal.
If.
I.
Want.
About.
Twelve.
Dividing.
Then.
We.
Very.
Simple.
You.
Just.
Drag.
See.
It.
Just.
Came.
Twelve.
Dividing.
Then.
Here.
I.
Want.
For example.
I.
Want.
To.
I.
Want.
To.
Ok.
I.
Want.
To.
This.
Then.
I.
Want.
Twelve.
Dividing.
Piece.
Then.
I.
Want.
To.
Directly.
Pick.
It.
Off.
You.
Will.
Find.
He.
Automatic.
To.
Connect.
He.
Automatic.
Connect.
Now.
Me.
I.
Pick.
This.
Side.
Then.
I.
Go.
To.
Adjust.
For example.
I.
Adjust.
To.
Four.
Dividing.
Hey.
Find.
Is it.
Directly.
Gave up.
It's very, very convenient.
And then we continue here.
For example, we just open, for example, 12.
You can change each side.
OK.
And then you can click to create.
Then it will be created.
And then the same.
The same.
I can continue to draw here.
Of course, if you have already created this, then you can't change the number of this side.
If you want to be like this just now, you didn't create it.
Then you can continue to draw like this.
For example, four points.
And then draw it like this.
And then you can choose it again.
For example, choose this one.
And then I set it to 12.
OK.
And then click to create.
Isn't that good?
Very, very fast.
This is a new feature added by MD.
But I personally think that you can add one.
For example, like the kind that can be smoothed, etc.
Such a function.
It seems that there is no such function now, right?
Yes.
Not yet.
But this is planned.
This is planned.
OK.
And then the network status is not good.
Is there a lag?
Not yet.
OK.
So there is no way.
That is to say, if we want to do this smooth now, you can only do it a little bit manually.
Smooth.
It's still hard.
But the function just now is very cool.
So there is a particularly good one besides this.
I personally think that the particularly good function of the drawing time is that it
As long as you have a top on the edge.
Yes.
It will show your number on the border that is related to it.
This is great.
Applause.
This function is great.
This function is simply the great function of drawing time.
So in this way, you can look at its number when you look at the top.
To do the top.
In this way, it guarantees that each of your sewing edges is the same number.
This is very, very, very convenient.
And it is symmetrical.
Someone asked just now, right?
Is this symmetrical?
Didn't you find it?
I just made the following piece.
Didn't you find that the top piece also appeared?
Right?
I move like this.
Did you see it?
The top and bottom are moving.
It is symmetrical with your board.
That is to say, as long as your board is symmetrical, it is symmetrical.
Isn't it very, very, very cool?
This function is really good.
If this is like what Xuelei said, it is the follow-up.
If there is a function such as smoothness, then this is god.
This is god.
Then this, then we can make a very smooth model line.
And then?
Including, we want, if we want to confirm this, then we will directly click on the right-hand side.
And then you can replace it, you can also clone it.
My personal suggestion is to say clone.
Then you click on it.
It will generate a model.
OK.
Then we quit this tool.
You will find that it generates a board at the original place.
This board is one.
This is one of our previous boards.
And then this board.
You can see the grid of this board.
Can you see it?
It's a horizontal number.
It's the grid we just pulled out.
In this way, you can make your whole grid like this.
And then direct it into this.
In this way, we can get a horizontal number inside MD.
A very good top.
Including if you have special needs.
You can also do it according to you.
For example, you want to make a game top.
Or you have some round faces in some places.
Or something.
You can increase or decrease the number in this.
All done in MD.
Very, very convenient.
Then this is some solutions provided to us internally by MD.
Some solutions provided internally.
Then the other is that we don't use MD's top.
We can also do similar operations outside.
It's just that there is no.
That is to say, all of your external operations do not have MD's top.
That is to say, the function of displaying the number.
There is no such function.
This is very regrettable.
All other software does not have this function.
All software does not have this function.
But we can use other software to get a top faster.
Because other software has some automatic top functions.
It can get a very good model.
Including some professional top software.
It's like this.
Just like the smart top tool.
It's smarter than MD.
Because there are some software like top gun.
It has this kind of function.
Because it was developed very early.
It has this kind of function a long time ago.
And then it develops it a little better.
It's better than MD.
So it's more useful.
We can take a look at it later.
I will show it to you.
OK.
Cloud can't be top.
Yes.
Because the user of cloud's face is not in the digital entertainment industry.
They don't need top.
They only need the final rendering.
You don't need to do complicated animation.
Right?
So you don't need it.
You can just use a pure triangular model.
The effect is already very good.
No need for top.
But if we do games in the afternoon.
Especially if you do games or movies.
If you do movies.
You can actually use it directly.
Just depends on your needs.
If you do games.
You can't use it directly.
Right?
So you need to go to top when you do games.
The difference between MD and cloud is here.
MD can output.
Can top.
Right?
You can output various model formats.
Then save or something.
Then what else?
It's UV.
Top.
These can be adjusted.
But in cloud.
It doesn't have these functions.
But what functions does cloud have?
It can do chess.
Put the code.
Right?
You can do it.
Like the internal V-ray rendering.
Yes.
The internal V-ray renderer.
You can render the picture.
You can export the CAD file.
Just go directly.
You can send it to the manufacturer.
Make you a template.
Something like that.
It's very convenient.
The corresponding industries of the two software are different.
So.
Its functions are all different.
We mainly use MD to do things.
We are in the entertainment industry.
Can top do games directly?
Can export and connect?
Yes.
For example, go to MD.com.
I don't understand.
I didn't look too well.
Don't worry.
I keep talking down.
Some of the specifics.
Today I was just talking about this kind of framework system.
Specific operations.
Or some of the same with the industry.
For example, some of the related projects.
What about project electronics?
It's here.
For example, everybody can add MD to the official group.
Discuss in the group.
If you want to add a group.
You can watch MD official.
The channel of Bilibli.
Let's go to the channel.
We will go again.
Are you really in the channel?
OK.
By the way.
I go to our channel.
Let's go to our channel.
I can install the information.
There is a QQ group on the channel of Bilibili
If you are interested, you can add a QQ group and discuss it together
These very detailed things are not suitable for us to discuss on the lecture table
It may waste time, I will continue to talk about it
Then let's continue to look down
There are actually a lot of external decoding solutions
There are a lot of external decoding solutions
Then we can automatically decode the external
We can also manually decode the external
But these two decoding solutions
We are decoding the fabric that is flat
After decoding, we need to let the flat fabric
To restore the shape of the clothes we wear on people
So there are two solutions
One is to use attribute transfer
To pass our decoded model back
The other is to use the way of packaging
Then all these operations
All these operations can be used
Use various software to mix
For example, automatic decoding
ZBrush has ZRemesher
Automatic decoding
3D Coat has automatic decoding
Maya also has its automatic decoding
Blender also has its automatic decoding
Its automatic decoding cannot be used
The built-in automatic decoding cannot be used
Automatic decoding can be used
And then the external manual decoding
Any software
As long as it is a multidirectional software
It can be manually decoded
We will demonstrate it later
Then based on attribute transfer decoding
For example, we are in Maya
In Max Blender
Can be based on attribute transfer
Can use attribute transfer functions
To pass
We will demonstrate Maya and Blender later
Then based on the way of packaging
As long as we have a software with a packaging transformer
Can be used
As long as there is a Blender shape
And packaging transformation
Can be used
Then let's demonstrate it
Let's demonstrate
First of all, let's take a look
The most common is to say
Directly import ZBrush
Then automatic decoding
Can generate a model
Let's take a look
But the automatic decoding model
In the case of the automatic decoding model
The number of steps is unsuitable
Is unsuitable
Let's take a look at some of the automatic decoding solutions
The most commonly used is
Everyone's favorite
Just put it in the ZBrush
Let's take a look
Let's delete this model of MD first
Then we
This 11
Goodbye 11
Already used
So don't use 11
Let's continue to turn on the 10
Then put this model out
Here, you need to
Adjust its UV a little
Clean up the UV
Because I want to put it in this little grid
Many people
Many people may be confused
Put it in that big grid
This is actually 0 to 1
Is this range
It's the smallest grid
I think its display
It's a little misleading
Let's click the right button first
The UV is placed in the 2D version
Position
Then we put it over
That's it
Then let's take a look
It doesn't seem to be very good
Then just do it
Just put it like this
This UV function
It's still better
Better
And then
Let's take a look
Then for example
Put it here
Whatever
I'll just put it down
Put it in the middle
That's it
OK
Then we go back to Simulation
Then we export this file
OBJ
Then we take this
For example
It's our high-end model
Save
Cover
Then remember
You have to choose a unified UV coordinate here
So that the UV will be exported
Otherwise
You are exported
There is no UV
I'm going to put it in the middle
Then we put it in the middle
OK
And then we put it in the middle
So we go back to Simulation
I feel A little bit away
We have to adjust this UV
It's close
We put the UV away
I'm afraid it will have a problem
OK
Then we're on the Simulation side
Then export
OBJ
Then choose our model
Click Yes
And then
Unified UV coordinates
Thin
Disconnect
Merge
Don't virtual model
Click confirm
In this case
We will export this model
So another
We need a version 2D
So we will be like this
Then flatten it
Click export
OBJ at this time
There is a UV. This whole thing has a UV. So it's according to this UV
You can call it UV or 2D, and then click save. And then here it is also not virtual models.
Combine the same size of the single target and the same size of the single target. Click OK. In this case, our flat model has also been exported.
In this case, it is satisfied with our original
The original file is satisfied with two original files, and then we can do some
This manual and automatic top, so let me first
To show
Let's demonstrate some automatic top plans first. Let me demonstrate some manual top plans first. Because manual top plans
It will be more
Convenient to demonstrate, manual top plans are not convenient to demonstrate. Let's demonstrate first, and then we will use automatic top plans to demonstrate it to everyone.
For example, if it is Maya, you can directly import the model just now
import
For example, like this
Wait a minute
File
import
And then we find this 2D
After this version comes in, you can see that it looks like this, and then we open it
Let me move it, because the one above is blocking me, I can't see it, and then we open it, and then at this time we can use it
The four-sided modeling tool in the modeling tool bag, and then the modeling can be done on this, which is very simple.
Then you can move like this
Then you can do this
That's it. This is the model. The last thing you do is a model here
Very, very simple and fast. Maya has a special top tool
This is Maya
Then Maya also has
On this web page, it has a four-sided drawing function
This is it
This number is too high, it may not be able to do it
This is a new addition to it, and it can also achieve an automatic top
Then this is Maya's manual top
So if it's in Blender
It's relatively
Because Blender doesn't have this
The corresponding one is the top tool that comes with it, so if you want to use its original function, it's actually using it as a dot-subject function
Then we are here
You can directly import it here, then OBJ, and then select
Our model
Then, remember to keep the order in the collection data here. It doesn't matter if it's a multi-layer group. After you click it
Then press the delete key
Then at this time, if you want to
Ah
Can't see above
Good luck
Then if you want to import it, it's very simple. You can just open the import and then
Then you can click on this called the top
This is the face import, then the activity is opened, and then
The independent elements of the project
Then move, rotate, and release, all open
In this case, then we are in
In the scene, you first see a square, and then press the TAB key, and then after all the squares are selected, press the M key to the center, and then we will give it
Move to the top, you can see that it is
Sucked on this
Then press the G key, then we press the E key to squeeze it out like this
You can squeeze it out like this
Then you can squeeze it to the top, and then you, for example, you select this edge, and then you click the right-click to divide it, you can also
This is up to you
Then, like this, then we can continue, for example, this E key
Squeeze it like this, then squeeze it like this, squeeze it like this, squeeze it like this, and then you count the number, and then you can do it with Maya, which is actually very similar
It's just that it's not as convenient as a special tool
Then you press the F key, F F F F
Just passed
But it
You can see that it is an insertion form, after all, it is sucked on this surface, so you can use this
There is one here, there is one here, there is one here
Visibility, not visibility, try to display
Then you change it to the front, and then you can change the color, for example, you change the blue color or something
Display?
Not displayed
Then we turn on the texture display here
The object is here, OK, so it will display this color, so if you edit it like this, it will be more convenient
You can squeeze it like this, right?
You can also squeeze it with a dot, including some keys, like the F2 key, and then it can do some, for example, you select a point
You press the F key, it will automatically come over like this, then you select
This way
The speed is still quite fast
Just press the F key like this
This is a similar function, and then you can slowly slowly go to the top
This is the Blender's
If you have to use Blender to top
And you can open this frame
You can see it more clearly
See it more clearly, and then you can adjust the semi-transparent or something, I won't say it anymore, because it's not too convenient to adjust the semi-transparent in the test picture
OK, then this is this
This is Blender's manual top
Of course you can also use Blender's top plug, Blender has a lot of top plugs, which are very useful, you can also go and have a look
These are two types of top, manual top mode, then we are talking about that automatic top, automatic top, then there are many common software that can be
Automatic top, for example
Our ZBrush
Then we are in
ZBrush
I just open a ZBrush
Just open a version
ZBrush every version of ZBrush has no problem
Yes, Max's automatic top is also quite useful, because Maya and Max have their own top functions, but Blender
No, right
You can't say it doesn't have it, it can do it, but it doesn't have a special top tool, which will be more trouble
You have to adjust a lot of things
Let's take a look, then in ZBrush, it's actually very convenient
Just click on this import and then
Find our model and then say this.obj
Open and drag it and press the T key
In this case, it comes in
It's that simple, you can see its frame with the Shift F key
Then directly on the
ZBrush editor here
ZRemesher
Then select the target multidirectional number and then click
You choose how many faces you probably want
Then you click it and it will give you a share
That's it, that's it, that's it, that's it, that's it, that's it, that's it, that's it
In fact, it's nothing, right?
Then the number of faces is too high, you click half and click again
OK, that's it
It's very simple, very simple, but there are some places where you may want to adjust it or something, which is normal, because it sometimes has some problems
Like this place
This place, right
There will be some
Small problems
OK, this is ZBrush, then you can just export it directly
There is this material
We are always trying to get a top with a flat horizontal value
This is our purpose
OK, then
Then I'll just use it, and I'll click the same thing
Half
A little less
Not as good as the one just now
But the number on the edge must be wrong
This is to pay special attention
This is it, this model, and then we just pour it out, for example, we think it is a good model
We are here, for example, this
For example, top
So our automatic top
The model appears, that's it
Then, like Maya, you can also do this kind of automatic top
Then let's talk about how to do it
Our flat
The model after the top
Whether it is your manual top or automatic top
How do we turn this model back to the shape of the clothes we used to wear on people before
How do we change
So here we will take a look, so first of all, let's talk about
First of all, we need to use a few tools, a few tools, first of all, the most original state, we will use a
Package tool and blend shape to achieve such a function
Then we need to talk about what a blend shape is
For example, I have a model here, then I copy it out
There is another model here, but this model, it may
For example
Made some
Small
This kind of
Different shapes
Then I want two models to merge and transform each other, so I will use a technology called blend shape
It is a fusion transformation technology, so on this transformation side
There is something called fusion transformation, if you choose these two objects and click on fusion transformation, then it will
Create a
Blend shape
Then this model
You can change it like this
Then you may be strange to say what is the reality principle of this thing
In fact, it is very simple, in fact, it is very simple, because our multi-dimensional it has a
Thing
Called
The top number
The main ID
Can you see it? We have an ID on each point, so
The function of blend shape is to find
The same ID point
To carry out a transfer
It's that simple
For example, we
Find this 253 this point
Then on this side, 253 this point is
Here, here, 253 this point is here
Then this point is here, then it actually is to overlap these two objects together, which is to let them
After clearing
One of them
From a point
Move it from the position of a to the position of b
This thing is called blend shape, it is called fusion transformation, this is such a technology
Then this technology is for us
What is the effect of the thing I just used?
In fact, it is very simple, we are here to the two of us just now
2D model 2D of this
Blending model
Model of our clothes just now
So what do these two models have in common? In fact, the number of their points is the same
The number of their points is the same, that is
That is to say we can
Achieve the same as the two balls just now
We can also achieve it in this
How to achieve it is very simple, we also give it a
You just choose two and then click on the fusion transformation
Or we can use the new function of Maya in this carving
Then you choose
Choose to create a fusion transformation, click on the add target, you don't have to click on the add target, we choose this
Then, yes, you still have to add a target
Then we choose this
Then do it
Then
How to do this
I forgot
You delete that model
This is
Then
I haven't done it for a long time, I forgot, and then it is
Create
Add the current selection as a target, OK
Then we hide it
In this case, we can achieve this object, see it
We can let these two objects switch between each other
Then you can find that this display is wrong, in fact, this is the problem of detection, you directly in this grid display
There is no problem, it is good
It's just like this
Wait a minute
Blending
Ok
So what does this do, then we have to talk about another function, we have to talk about another function called the package function
It's been an hour, I have a little more content to prepare, what is the concept of the package? For example, I have such a piece
Then I have another object
For example, I have a ball here
Ok, so if I use a package tool, for example, I choose this ball, I choose this piece, and then I want to let this piece affect this ball
We use the package tool on the deformation side
So what will happen? That is, our piece
You can affect this ball
This thing is called a package
Wrap
Package
So after having this function, have you already thought about how we deal with these two models?
Right?
Have you thought about it? Have I thought about it?
So let's put it first
Open it, right?
And then we
Introduce the model of the automatic top in our Zbrush just now
This
Is it coming in?
Just
This one, right?
This is the model of our automatic top
So how to operate it? Right? How to operate it?
Then we choose to look at
These two models, right?
We choose it first, right? Then choose it again
We want to let the model that can change just now, use this one
The model behind this model to wrap the model in front
So we have to choose first
The object that is wrapped
Then select the object that is wrapped
Then we click transform and then click wrap
After that, we put the fusion transformation
A bit stuck
Done
Oh no
Okay, okay
Then after that, we put this model
See it?
See it? After wrapping it, we transform it back
Deng deng deng deng
Is it?
Just got a model of our automatic top
The shape of wearing clothes
Right?
This is the earliest
This is the earliest way we use
Is to carry out such a transmission
But
There is something bad about this transmission
it
Very
How to say
Its logical relationship
There are several layers of logical relationship
And if your fabric is layer by layer
That is, you
There are many layers of this kind of fabric on it
Or you have some
Selfish
If you have a little bit of interspersed fabric
This method is not very convenient
It will have some
Uncertain or
Especially in
In the process of wrapping
There may be some small problems
Then
How to do this?
Then another method was applied
What is the other method?
Use attribute transfer
Then I'm still in Maya
Let me show you first
Wait a minute, I'm all in Blender
Reveal it all again
Blender can do it all
Let you see Maya first
Because I operate Maya more skillfully
ZB can also top
All can
But this dress has a gap
That's right, this dress has a gap
So I prefer to say manual top
You can use MD's
Hand-to-top
To top
I didn't say what I was going to say
Let me show you
You can use MD's manual top or use top-hand top
Then count the numbers
Then use this way to pass it to him
It's very convenient
All methods can be mixed with each other
Which one do you want to use
Not to force you
Do you have to use this or that
According to your own needs
OK
And then we invented another way
That is, we directly use
We directly use
The way of attribute transfer to carry out such a transfer
So what does attribute transfer mean?
Let's continue to import this object here
Let's import one first
Our high-end model
This is our high-end model of this dress
We don't need to use Blendship here
Then we import another dress
2D version of this
A model
OK and then we import another
Such a model
Three models
Delete this set
In case of problems
Then these three models
What is the concept of attribute transfer?
In three-dimensional software
Our two similar objects
It can be through a certain similar attribute
To match
Then perform another attribute matching
For example, if these two objects are equally similar
We can match it
The location of each point
For example
The position of these two objects is the same
That is, their shapes are the same
Although they are not the same
But the shape is the same
Then I can pass through its shape to transmit its UV
This is a concept called attribute transfer
Then in Maya
It can make an attribute transfer
Then here on the grid
It has a function called attribute transfer
How do we use the function of attribute transfer?
Then there is a point here
That is, our flat and worn clothes
It has a common point
That is, they both have UV
The common point of these two models is that they both have UV
Then what is the common point of the object that we have applied
What is the common point of this flat object?
It's the same shape
Right? It's the same shape
Isn't that it?
If we want to make
The object that has been applied
It becomes its shape directly
Then we will use this middle model as a transfer point
Right?
We let
We let it first
Let's let this middle key
This 2D
This 2D object
What does it pass to our top good object?
We want to pass UV
What is it based on? Based on its shape
After we click on the application
We will pass this UV to our top good model
You can see that this top good model did not have UV before, right?
We automatically top
There is no UV
At this time, UV is transmitted to it
Then at this time I have UV
What is the common point of this object and this object?
Its UV is the same
Then we can pass it again
Pass it again
To its UV space
Pass its top position
Then click on the application
You can see that our object is passed
See?
This is
Passing in the way of attribute transfer
This is another way
This method can be written directly into a script
So basically it can achieve one-click transfer
This is a relatively quick way
But that is to say, you have to understand why I do this
After you understand it, you will find that this thing is very simple
Very simple and very fast
We use a lot
A lot of such ideas to do this plug
So basically in AMD
In that MD export and then to ZB
To that
In Maya, you just need to do a good top model and put it in
Then
A few frames and a little bit of output
It's done for you
Very convenient
OK
These are the two ways
The two ways of attribute transmission
Then these two ways of attribute transmission
In Blender
You can do the same
There is no difference
First of all, let's
Demonstrate the first one
Then we import
OBJ
Then we select this model just now
For example, let's import our high model first
Let's first look at the way of Blendshape and deformation
wrong
I forgot to choose
I forgot to set the attribute
So we are here to import
We have to select
This is the collection data
It is always defaulted every time
I often forget
Then you have to keep the top order
Because we want that top ID
Do you remember the top ID that I showed you just now?
I want that ID
Then we import OBJ
Then we select this one that we just flattened
The same
We want this thing
import
Then these two objects are together
So how do we do that Blendshape just now?
You can do the same
In Blender
It's called the shape key
Called key shape
It's the same as Blendshape
We click on this
Click first
Have a basic shape
Because if you do the key shape
First of all, you have to have a primitive basic shape
Otherwise you can't do it
Just like Maya just now
You have to click first
Then you choose two objects
Activate this object at the same time
The orange one must be
Not orange
It's a lighter yellow
Be sure to activate this
This object
Then here we can
Click on this little triangle here
Combine as a shape
In this case, we hide it in H
In this case, the key of this object
There is one in the shape
We just have this screen
Can you see it?
It's exactly the same as the one in Maya just now
Then we put it here
We put it here
Then we are here
Involve another
OBJ and then select the object we just opened
Involve
Let's take a look
At this time, do we have two models?
One of this and one of this
This model can be changed
What about the other one
Is our
One
Just
Open the frame
This is like this
Right
OK then
Then the following is to achieve the effect of a package
Then how to achieve the package
We are on the model of this top code
We are in the transformer here
Then there is one called surface deformation
Surface Deformed
Such a one
This transformer
Then we choose the target
The object we can transform just now
Remember to click
Binding
Then we are here
Go to this object
Give him this
Turn off
Can you see it?
In this case, we will get a
Good package
Such a model
Then the same operation
Right
Blender can do
The same
The concept is the same
The operation is almost the same, right?
In fact, they are all the same
In addition to this
In addition to this, how do you do the function of attribute transfer just now?
Then this is needed to intervene
This is needed to intervene
This is a plug-in of Blender
If you do it directly, Blender does not have this function
Blender can't do attribute transfer or say its attribute transfer is more
Special
It is a complete attribute transfer
It can't be based on which ship
If it wants to transfer, it will transfer together
But it has this function in its internal framework
So there is a person who wrote a plug-in
This plug-in can achieve this function
Let's take a look
Then here we still import
Just now
Our or our
Or our this file
We are here
Then we found the retopo
Copy
Then we just have that high-end
Then
Keep the order
Open import
Ok
Then we have a plug-in name in this Blender
It's called Mesh Data Transfer
Mesh Data Transfer
This plug-in is a free plug-in that can be downloaded from Gumroad
It is a free plug-in of Blender
Then this plug-in is also very easy to use
Take a look at this menu
Do you think
I'm so familiar with this one and this one and this one and this one and this one and that one is exactly the same, right?
In fact, it is the same
I remember this is a
Movie producer
To develop
Because this is in the movie production
Data transfer
This function is
Very common
If not, it will be very
Very disturbing
So he made a plug-in of this Blender
This plug-in is used by everyone
Just download it from his Gumroad
No money
Then we are here
Just import just now
Model
Then we can do it
Similar operation just now
Then we put this
Still click import
Ok ok
Import in
Then we import again
UOBJ
Then this is our
Assuming that the top is good
In fact, it is an automatic top
Then how do we need to operate at this time?
We need to go
For example, we have this object
This object
And this object
Right?
Then we directly select this object
Then let's take a look
He has no UV
This object has a UV, this one has no UV
I want to give him his UV and then give him his shape
Right?
Look at the upper right corner
Then I will take a look at this object first
We are here
Open our
UV interface
Then here we look at our UV editor
Then you press the type key
You can see that there is a UV object here
But this object has no UV
Then this object
There is also a UV
Then at this time I need to go
These two objects
You have to activate your
Target object
Then we
Click on our source
Ok then what do we want to transfer?
We want to transfer UV
Based on what?
Based on the world environment or
There is a problem here
That is, we are in the Blender
All the objects that are導入进来OBJ
It is rotated 90 degrees
Because it is Z-axis above
So here we have to select all the objects
Ctrl A and then change it all
Let it clear here
In this case, it is more convenient for us to transmit
Then
In fact, you can just select it like this
It's your two objects
Its source is this Hi2D
Then we based on the world environment
Transfer UV
After you click
He is wrong
Still have to select both
Activate this object
There is a problem here, that is, there is no UV object, it is in the Blender
It's empty here, that is, it doesn't have a UV slot
So he can't send information in
You need to create one
OK then we are here
Click again
Then we will press the Tape key, you will see this top good object, UV will be transmitted
This is not needed
Then these two objects, that is, I want to give it its shape, right
Then it's very simple, let's change this source
Let's change the source
Adjust to the top
Then we based on Active UV
What to transmit
Transfer Shape
Then this Transfer Shape here can even create a Key Shape for you
But the premise is that you have to create one in the Key Shape
If you don't create this slot, it is not there
It will be wrong
OK, then we will click this at this time
You can click this as well
Click this is correct
Direct transfer, click this will be transferred to a Key Shape
Then we click
In this way, it will pass, then we will hide the original
We will find that this object is also transmitted like this
Then in this Key Shape, it also gives you a Key Shape, which is what we just clicked
The face number is relatively high, it may be a bit laggy
It feels like this
OK
Then you can see
Maya and Blender can do the same effect
The same effect, we all realized this effect
You can also pass UV without the X key, right?
Is it true?
I'll try it next time
Then this is the demonstration in Blender
In the demonstration in Blender, I just said that I want to show you the Topogon
Because in fact, the new top function of MD11 is very similar to the top function of Topogon
But Topogon is easier to use
So under the premise that MD11 has not been updated yet, we can use
Topogon to carry out a manual top
Here to demonstrate
Then my Topogon
This is Topogon
Topogon is very convenient to do that kind of
Counting numbers, this type of top is very convenient because Topogon Samsung adds a function, we first
Insert a
Load reference mesh
Then this reference mesh, we import the high-model object that we need to import
Then click here
This
Open
So our model comes in, then the test operation of Topogon and Maya is the same, Alt plus left key, Alt plus middle key, Alt plus right key
OK
Then we click here
Add number, so a new object is built, we can operate it on it
So why do I say
Topogon is more convenient because it has one more
This function is called patch function
This patch function is very useful
And the patch that we see in MD11 is actually the same function, it can also be drawn like this
But what's the difference
It's not connected to a straight line between two points, but it records your path
This is very convenient, for example, we want to be here
1, right
This is better to do with a digital pen
OK
Then you press the Ctrl key
You can adjust it for him
See this
This is more convenient than MD11
When will MD11 learn
Then use this brush
Then
Just that
You need to click the Enter key
Then we use this brush
Use this
Not a knife, we can use this brush to brush it
In this case, in fact, to a certain extent, it can be achieved in a faster way
This is more convenient than that
The top of MD11 is more convenient, but there is a problem that you need to manually count the parameters
You have to count this parameter
Then if you want to smooth it
For example, you can zoom in on this right key
Then you can adjust the strength of the middle key
Adjust the strength of the middle key
Then turn off the border and press the Shift key
Super fast
This is the function of the Topogun
I still recommend the Topogun
So look forward to the follow-up of MD11
If you can update
For example, this kind of smooth function like this
That's too convenient, then we don't need any other software
All functions can be achieved directly within MD11
Well, that's it for the part I want to share today
I may speak a little fast, but this has a recording, so if you have any parts that are not clear, you can go back and watch the recording
In MD, the official Bilibili has it
That's it
Well
Do you have any questions?
Yes, do you have any questions?
Buy
Oh OK
Why are all the answers learned?
Yes, the package function is not only for packaging materials
For example, you make a physical zipper or you make a button or you make any pattern or that kind of border
You can use the package function to pack it on the clothes
It's very convenient
For example, let's look at this just now
I just said that I forgot to talk about this, it's actually quite convenient, for example, we are here to import
Then, for example, this 2D
For example, import
3D
3D 3D
Well this
For example, these two, it can't do that brand shape
Transform and transform
OK and then
Isn't it like this? Then what I just said is that
For example, you make a
For example, make a zipper
I'm going to start making a soul zipper
Soul modeling
For example, this is a zipper
For example, add a lot of diamond
Then, for example, you put
For example, this is a good model for tofu, I won't cover the process of tofu, you choose it and then you choose it
Then you use this packaging tool in the deformation
In fact, for example, if you use this brand shape, you can wrap your zipper on the clothes
See
Then you can pack any object, this is a very convenient function
Ah
Including for example
Make a small button
Something like this is here
Then
Make a small button
I choose it
Choose it and then wrap it here
You can just go up like this
Very convenient
In addition to the manual, there are good processing methods, there are no good processing methods, you can only do it manually
Now
Now you can only do it manually for the time being
But after you count the number of frames, it's actually very fast. Many software have similar functions. As long as you have the same number of frames, you can directly look at the street.
I don't want to copy these two objects, for example
And then
You just have to choose this side
Then choose this side
Then look at the street
As long as you have the same number of frames, you can look at it
You can look at it, no problem
Even including like
You may think that the two objects are flat, but it's not. As long as you are like this, you can use this bridge
Then you can do this
Then you can also adjust the type
Linear, you can adjust it to merge
It can be like this
Including curve, right?
What
Merge
Then you can also adjust what to trace
In fact, it is quite convenient. Blender can also be the same. In fact, as long as the number is the same, it can be
OK
Is there any more questions?
If you want to send a message, you can watch the playback of the live broadcast later. Let me say it again.
It doesn't mean to say it again
There is a video
There are also many tools in the Yang River that can help you do these works
Then MD's class
MD's official class also gives a full-length version software for a month. You can also take a look if you are interested.
What are the benefits of this full-length version software? You can immediately launch the latest version and update all the features of the latest version immediately, right?
If you use it, you can't go back, tell you
MD11 may go back occasionally
MD11
It's a bit stuck
But next week
It should be a new version
If I remember correctly
It will be a patch version
Will be more optimized
In fact, his model drawing idea is very good. After it is done, it should be more efficient.
Then there is also my MD class. If you are interested, you can take a look and take everyone to make a model
Take everyone to make clothes
Then everyone is saying that it will be a sewing machine. Really will teach
It's easy to show you how to use a sewing machine
Then there is the official MD and this
Lert Studio
This game is interesting. You can take a look. In fact, this game
It's easy because I don't think there are many people involved.
And you want to judge that there are our own people in it, right?
I hate me I hate me
I'm kidding. This snow pear is very fair. It's impossible to hate
Should be
If I find out who is my own, you are
For example, in the lower left corner of the clothes
Just hit
Snow pear or s
I will identify
Identify out
You heard it
Will the recording be cut off in this section?
Will not be cut off
Just put it there
Anyway
They don't understand Chinese
This game is a global game
Global game
Yes, it is a global game
Every month there will be
Different themes
Yes, this month's theme is cyberpunk and then sign up before May 5th
So if you want to participate, you can sign up earlier
But if the work is submitted, it is not so early
The work is submitted, it seems to be No. 15
It seems to be
Then do you have any other questions?
If there are any other questions, you can also add our QQ group
But
But a big group in a group
What is this group
Video left corner
There is a left corner of the live broadcast or you can add a big group
A big QQ group
Ok
Then if you want to see MD's, this is some small skills or some small cases, then in MD's official
There are many, many in the video of Bilibili
There are 75 videos
A large number of this small teaching and lecture videos are all free. If you are interested, you can take a look.
A lot of things are very beautiful
Ok, then you worked hard today.
Everyone remember to pay attention to Ada's Bilibili account official account
Thank you thank you thank you for giving me this opportunity to do this lecture here. Thank you very, very, very much.
Oh, we are very grateful to Ada to come to us to give us a lecture
Thank you
You are too polite
Thank you thank you thank you
Thank you everyone for looking at me here
Ok ok ok then I'll skip it
Ok ok then look forward to the next live broadcast
Ok ok ok ok ok ok ok ok
Thank you, bye bye, thank you everyone, thank you, thank you, thank you, bye bye
Wait a minute
Ok thank you
Then I will end Tencent here first
Ended
Wait a minute, everyone
Here I am
I want to talk about
Take out
Oh no
I want to talk about my part
I want to talk about how to make a skirt today
You won't
Forget it all
Do I have to find some background music to play
The part I talk about will also be very fast
Wait a minute
There may be some confusion
I'll go find a background music to play
Wait a minute
What kind of background music do you play
My songs seem to be
There is no kind of
Wait a minute, wait a minute, very fast, very fast
I don't seem to have that kind of
I listen to my songs and fall asleep
No no no
My songs are really all songs that will fall asleep
Next voice
OK
OK OK wait a minute
Just use this background music
But this background music can't hear me talking
Hello hello
Yes, the part I'm talking about is
The class can also do
If the background music is too loud, you can talk to me
Then let's start talking about my part
If you have any questions, you can put it in the live broadcast process
I will answer the chat
Let's start talking now
First of all, if you make a skirt, we have a premise
No matter what kind of short skirt you make
That is, our skirt is divided into two parts
One is the upper body and the other is the lower body
If you do half a skirt, you can only do the lower body
First of all, we are going to make a belt
When everyone is making a belt, you must pay attention to it
No matter what kind of skirt you make, you have to do this belt first
You can use this belt as a basis and then do the back part
Understand?
So the basis we are going to do is to do this belt first
Then we can solve things later
So how do we make a belt
First of all, you use
This square
Long-shape board
In the 2D window, draw the board according to the silhouette of the human body
The silhouette of our human body is actually seen from the front view
So it can't calculate the thickness of the side
Because there is no way to calculate the thickness of the side
Our belt
Because if you
If you want to use it conveniently, you must be symmetrical on the left, right?
So this board is the length of one side
That width is basically the 3 times or 2.5 times the thinnest part of the human waist
Understand?
Then after doing this belt, select this belt and press Ctrl D to create a symmetrical board
After creating a symmetrical board
We are going to arrange the belt on the arrangement point of the waist
After arranging
Because it's a little far from the body, so you have to make the shoulder strap a little smaller
Otherwise it will pass through the human body
Passed through
Can't wear
So now we sew it
After sewing
When we make a skirt, the belt is definitely not loose, it is attached
If it is attached, you must reduce the surface of the virtual model shoulder
This way we can ensure that the belt of this skirt is close to the human body
Understand?
it is good
After we finished the belt
We are going to shrink it a little bit, so that it becomes an attached state
It can't be loose
This is the same as we usually wear skirts anyway
After that
After that, we can press Alt 7 to open the pressure map and the force map
After opening it, we won't see this place
Green yellow
That is to say
There is a table here
The value of this table is
If the blue part
The grid
That place is not stretched
But the color is closer to red
The more stretched this place is, the more serious it is
Sometimes when we make skirts
We must make sure that this belt is
It is relatively close to the human body
At least it can't be deformed to red
Because if you
If you deformed to a red area, then every time we draw a board, we will not start with this belt as a basis
The size of your painting will be
wrong
It may be deformed
It doesn't look very good
So we have to
Adjust the belt to fit the human body as much as possible
The main grid color is mainly blue
Then you can see it visually
It's not loose
Making a belt is the basis of making a skirt
Everyone must remember
Then we will reduce the particle diameter and the impact thickness
The impact thickness is actually a bit similar to the surface diameter
It is the air thickness around the board
This value is usually set to 1 in the process of doing it
it is good
After the belt is done, we can start making skirts
Here we are going to make a bag skirt
How to make a bag skirt
That is to say
We can draw by hand
Then your front and back can use the same board first
We use a multidirectional first
Then because the front and back use the same
Board shape
So we just draw half of the waist here
When you create a board
Your mouse will have a red line here
It is called the intelligent guide line
It is to remind you of the end point of a board
Or match with other boards
Then we will start to draw the board
When drawing, I usually
For example, this is a bag skirt
Because it is more
This is the interface of MD11
Because it is a more
Tight board
So I will basically stick to the body curve to draw
Because it is a bag skirt
We will learn to make a bag skirt first
The back skirt will be a little easier
Because this
There is a lot of content in today's live broadcast
I will talk about a lot of skirts
So everyone may be a little sleepy
Wake up
When I was drawing a skirt
Because I want to refer to the curve of the human body
So we are in the window of the second floor
You put the belt first
Put it close
It will be more convenient to draw according to this curve
I just talked about it
The human body is thick
So in our skirt just
It's in the belt here
We are attached to the human body
So you must know
If you draw the middle line here
Then as long as the width here is equal to the width
Then your side
This thickness has already been calculated
In the middle
This part is also recorded
It's calculated
So we can rest assured that we can draw according to this body shape
In the workshop, we used to have a video
You can translate it in the previous video
Then when we are making skirts
You don't have to press the Ctrl key to create a curve point
But in the process of doing it, don't use all the curve points
Because if you use all the curve points
It will be very troublesome when you adjust the points later
Because of the curve point
In our software, when you edit the version, you always use the edit straight line as a reference
So this one
We need to hit a few breakpoints in the skirt
So that
Guaranteed
Will not affect
Other points
Understand?
So we will hit a breakpoint in some key parts, such as the position of the hip
And the widest position of the thigh
Hit another breakpoint
Add it to the knee position and hit a breakpoint
Draw it like this
If you look at it with the edit version, there will only be three straight lines
One two
Four
One two three four
These four breakpoints
Because that's the only way we can adjust the middle edge
It won't affect other edges
Understand?
So no matter if you are making a skirt or a top
You have to hit a few more breakpoints in the middle
You will know how to hit these breakpoints later
After drawing, CTRL D
Create a symmetrical version and then copy and paste
And then arrange them on the back
These are all the operations you know
Then we will be faster
Move
After putting it down, we can sew the version down
Like a belt
A place that can't be used
Where you don't want it to transform
Just freeze it
We sew the sides and the front and back
After sewing, it is now a skirt
Is it easy?
In fact, when we draw, we can mainly refer to the 2D human figure
After we finished drawing, I will take a look at the pressure chart
When we open the pressure chart
You see our back
Because we use the same version of the front and back
But our model, especially the 2D model
Its hip waist is
Very big difference
The front and middle are flat
But the hips may be more plump
In the case of the hips, if we use the same version as the front, then its size is not right
It will have a problem with stretching and deformation
So if we are making this kind of skirt
I hope it won't be so tight
When
We will adjust the back
No matter if you are making skirts or clothes, it is the same
If you see this place
There is a red area
Basically it is to deal with it
Because if you don't deal with it, there may be some unstable problems
Hello everyone wake up
So what we are going to do is to choose the side curve first and then choose these lines
Pull them out
So that we can widen the back
Understand?
Because if we say that the curve on the side is not right
Its size
If there is a difference, there will be some wrinkles around this gap
Appear
Understand?
So we have to make sure that the curve on the side is as correct as possible
We can pull it
Until there is basically no red here
There is no red area
After adjustment
We
Ok
The next thing we have to do is to adjust the back
Because when we widen the back piece
Because it is not the same as the width of the belt
So there will be some stretch wrinkles here
What's next? We have to learn how to make a rope
The rope is able to let the clothes above
Structure of a vertical structure
Because now the length of our belt is probably longer than the original half of our belt.
Because this side is extended outwards, do you understand?
So after this side becomes longer, we have to dig a part on top of it to match its length.
So there won't be these wrinkles.
So, so, so add a straight line here.
After adding a straight line and selecting it with the edit panel, there is an increase in the right-click.
For the increase, we click to confirm.
The width of this extension is the difference between the whole side and the length here, do you understand?
So after we dug a triangle, this side plus this side is equal to the side we just made.
In fact, the length is the same.
In the case of the length being the same, it is not easy to have wrinkles.
Let's take a look.
Here, if we go directly to the simulation, because the line is not right, so it will have some strange places.
So we have to re-create the line.
In the process of sewing, press the Shift key to sew more and more.
Now let's activate it again.
You can see that the grid here is basically blue and green, and the red part is relatively small.
This is more suitable for the human body.
Then we can see that this rope is a triangle.
And then when we put this triangle together, this strip will arch up.
When it is arched up, it will fit the structure of the human body.
But now we will see that there is a sharp point protruding out of this place.
It's because this rope is not long enough.
It's not smooth enough.
This sharp point will jump up.
So what we have to do is very simple.
You find out where the widest part of your buttocks is.
You can click on the board.
For example, after I click here, I will move this point to the widest part of the buttocks.
Now I'm going to simulate whether it fits the buttocks.
Did you learn it?
Learn to type 1.
Do you understand?
In short, this is the place where you have to dig a triangle and then put it up.
OK.
Now we can see that the whole skirt is specially fitted.
And it doesn't have an over-stretching problem.
This can also help us.
In fact, whether it is the buttocks or the waist,
because some models, such as clothes,
your chest is relatively large and your waist is relatively thin.
You are also digging a board in the middle.
In short, as long as you know that you add a rope here,
you can make it fit.
Because it's like this.
Imagine this.
This is our buttocks.
Is there a lot of fabric here?
And the waist is relatively thin.
So there must be less fabric on the waist.
Do you understand?
So we have to dig a piece in the middle.
There will be a loop.
And if you don't understand here,
we will have a teaching video.
I will also talk about it in the teaching video.
What about before optimization?
Before the optimization.
Yes.
The part of the
top.
After that, we will modify the line on the side.
Okay, let's freeze the top board first.
Now, because you will see it on the side here.
If this skirt is actually,
because this place is empty.
So this board will be here.
There is a twisty feeling.
In fact, it is because it is not suitable for the human body.
So the curve does not look very good.
Next, we are going to learn how to modify the curve.
Then modify the curve.
Do you remember that I gave it a point before?
So we can adjust it separately.
Here I can find its point.
Now it is not.
Just a protruding piece.
So let's put this curve point in.
Let's put it in.
Okay.
After these two points are collected,
when we start the simulation,
is it that it is attached here?
After this line is processed,
we will go to the next point.
There is a structure like a stoop here.
Right?
Then what we have to do is smooth it out.
Do you understand?
Okay.
If we move this point directly at this time,
then this point will definitely affect the whole line.
So here,
we can change a tool.
There is a tool called round-shape curve.
It is a round-shape curve tool.
It can smooth out a corner.
After it is smoothed out,
we start the simulation.
You can see that there are still some,
well,
it may look like there are some bumps.
We can round it out with the editor-in-chief tool.
Okay.
The next way is to repeat the previous operation.
For example,
what is the increase of the curve point,
and then fix the point here,
and also move these straight lines.
You can see that I have added some breakpoints below,
so the modification here on the top
will not affect the bottom.
So when you are making clothes,
you must hit more.
When you have time,
you can hit more straight lines.
For example,
when you don't want to affect other curves,
just add some more straight lines.
Okay.
Let's look at the simulation again.
In the end,
you can see that it is basically smooth here.
And then the straight line point,
after we use it,
we are going to convert these useless straight lines
into curve points.
Okay.
After converting them into curve points,
we will simulate it again.
If there are more corners,
we will round this corner
with the curve point.
Just like this protruding corner,
we will round it with the curve point.
Then we will modify it little by little.
After we modify it little by little,
we can see that the curve point at the end
is very smooth.
Do you understand?
Ah.
The point is that you can use the original curve tool
and hit some more breakpoints.
Um.
After making the skirt of the bag skirt,
I want to see what we are doing later.
Um.
I suddenly can't remember.
Oh.
Don't delete these straight lines here.
If it is used to control,
you have to convert it directly into a curve point,
not delete it.
Because if you delete the straight lines,
its points will not match.
Do you understand?
Okay.
Oh.
Wait a minute.
I pick up a phone call.
You don't know if this phone call
is a very important thing, right?
Wait a minute.
I have to call you.
Sorry.
I'll call you.
Hello.
Can you hear me?
Hello, hello.
Okay.
Oh.
There will be a asked question
for the skirt of the bag skirt.
Yes.
Okay.
Hello.
Uh.
Yes, I just got a call from someone asking me if I want to buy a car, and I said that I don't need it at that time, and then this project file can be saved, and then we will use this file often.
Okay, let's merge the money in. After merging, let's try how to make this skirt into a tight skirt.
First of all, when we are making a tight skirt, we have to pay attention to adjust the side a little tighter.
Then only when the side becomes tighter, that is, the entire width becomes tighter, you can make it look tight.
Understand?
It sounds like it doesn't make sense.
Then it's like this.
I'm adjusting it.
In the process of adjusting, I won't move the curve here like the waist.
I usually move the two lines at the bottom of the side.
Understand?
That is, we won't adjust a whole side.
Because if you adjust a whole side, it won't match the waist here again.
Understand?
Because this side, we just don't move it.
Just move it in here, it will be tight.
It's tight in this place.
Otherwise,
our waist can't match it.
Isn't there a wrinkle in this place?
Understand?
So we just move these two sides at the bottom.
After moving, if you see that because we want it to be tight,
it's going to be very similar to such a wrinkle.
On the one hand, here is where we are going to move these two points inside.
Make it a tighter one.
Then there is another reason.
There is another thing.
That is, we will pull this skirt up a little bit.
So that there will be a wrinkle pile.
Okay.
If you pull the chain, we use it in any video.
You can open a video and take a look at it.
You will see it.
Okay.
After it is tight, we will put the bottom in.
Just put the corner here so that it can't be seen.
And then the skirt, we will make it a little shorter.
Because this kind of skirt is usually shorter.
It's not that long.
Then we will reduce the diameter to 10.
Reduce the length to 1.
Then you can see that it will be a little wrinkled while it is tight.
There will be some wrinkles.
And this is relatively flat.
There will be some strange wrinkles.
After that adjustment, we will manually drag the plate.
Okay.
Then when the particle diameter is relatively small.
If this dress is too tight, too tight.
There will be some obvious ones here on the waist.
You see, I already have a little bit here.
So our waist here is definitely not able to move it inside.
Because if it is too tight, it will show the model's expression.
The surface looks a little strange like this.
Another point is that sometimes I see a lot of people making clothes.
They like the side is invisible.
As long as there are some very similar wrinkles here.
If that's the case.
Then you open this function here.
Then along the flat wrinkles here.
Click to drag your mouse.
Here we make the size a little smaller.
The width is also a little smaller.
Along this side.
Add it along this side.
Then you can apply a little more to the point.
Then while you are touching.
You can flatten the wrinkles here.
Isn't it amazing?
Well, but for me personally.
I definitely think there should be wrinkles on the side.
But if you want to smooth out the wrinkles.
You can use this method.
It can only be used on the side.
It can't be used on the front here.
Just here in front.
You have to know.
This is a very similar wrinkle.
It's because the side is tight.
One is on the horizontal direction.
It's tight.
There's another one on the vertical direction.
I intentionally put this skirt up.
I raised it a little bit.
That's why there's a lot of wrinkles like this.
So the reason it's produced.
It's because the two sides have a lot of force.
Pull this piece of cloth again.
But the wrinkles here.
Because it's made of fabric.
It's not formed by force.
So we can use the iron to move it away.
Understand?
This kind of bigger one is hard to move away.
And it wasn't flat at first.
How come now.
After the wrinkles.
I have to get rid of it again.
Okay.
And then finally.
Let's add a flower edge to it.
After the tortoiseshell is finished.
Use the tortoiseshell directly.
Use the right arrow to delete it.
Then we just need to create a relatively long rectangle.
After sewing it up.
It's a flower edge.
The flower edge.
This thing.
You can't just simulate it.
You can just simulate it.
You can see this board.
It's through the front of the human body.
All the way to the back.
So you have to arrange it.
It's arranged on the side.
Otherwise, you can just simulate it.
It's going to shake all the time.
Understand?
After sewing.
We can reduce its particle diameter a little bit.
And sew it together in the front and the back.
You must be thinking.
Why do I always sew the top and bottom.
The board is sewn on the side at the end.
The reason is very simple.
It's because I often forget.
Nothing else.
So after you finish sewing.
Remember to check.
Did you miss it?
Did you miss the sewing line?
Then we can reduce the particle diameter.
Now.
Because of my skirt.
Before.
I adjusted the elastic strength of the skirt very high.
When the elastic strength is relatively high.
The number of wrinkles appears.
It will be more.
And these wrinkles look very hard.
Then our skirt.
Here.
The board is like a flower.
Usually its shape is relatively soft.
The whole curve is very soft.
So we will copy it separately.
Two boards.
Then apply the elastic strength to it.
Reduce it a little.
Make it look softer.
Understand?
Then bend the strength.
We will also reduce it a little.
These are all to make the fabric look softer.
So everyone is in the process.
Be sure to understand.
What kind of type do you want to do?
What kind of type does it belong to?
Is it easy to have wrinkles?
Or is it not easy to have wrinkles?
If it looks soft overall.
Then its top six properties are generally relatively low.
What kind of fine fine sand strength.
And what kind of this.
This is relatively low.
Another point.
Is that we can adjust the deformation intensity of the board separately.
Deformation intensity.
Do you usually never change it?
Then I can explain it to you.
Deformation intensity means that.
It is related to the bending intensity.
It is the percentage of bending intensity.
For example, this is 17.
Then.
The deformation intensity below is 33.
Then it is 33% times this period.
Then it will shrink.
Then whose property does it shrink to?
It is for the fold that has been formed.
It will not affect your overall fold.
It will only affect the fold that has been formed.
Understand?
So when we shrink it.
If you start the simulation.
Its fold will collapse overall.
Its fold will become very thin and very soft.
But it only affects the fold.
Does not affect the shape of the whole fabric.
If you want it to be softer.
You can continue to reduce its deformation intensity.
Okay.
Then let's take a look at how to divide ordinary dresses.
There are many dresses.
For example, like a cheongsam.
You may open the side.
That is, its side is open.
The structure of this opening is very easy to do.
You can just adjust the deformation line.
Or delete the deformation line.
There is a loop.
And we will have a summary at the end of each lesson.
Well.
This is the operation mode of the later dubbing.
So there is.
Whether it is a live broadcast or a course.
There will be.
Well.
Uh.
Pongpong skirt.
There will be later.
It's a bit similar to the result of Pongpong skirt.
I'll talk about it later.
It's added.
It's added pressure.
It's not sharp.
Okay.
Uh.
Next, let's make a draw dress.
Okay.
The draw dress is like this.
Uh.
First of all.
When we make a draw version.
We will use the previous one.
Uh.
This high.
Hey.
What is this skirt called?
Pongpong skirt.
Formed.
That is, the Pongpong skirt learned in the first lesson.
It will be used often later.
So you must save it after you finish it.
After saving it.
I will dig the rope behind it.
Just delete it.
Because.
The last look of this skirt.
Is.
Like this.
So.
There is no need to leave a rope behind it.
It's not a special one overall.
It's a look that is very tight on the body.
So we're going to delete the rope.
Otherwise.
It will mainly.
It will affect the version we create later.
After deleting the rope.
We'll just re-recognize it.
Okay.
And then fire simulation.
After that.
The belt that can't be used.
The belt is frozen.
After it's frozen.
In fact.
It's very easy to make this pleated skirt.
All we have to do is.
On the tree.
Just stretch the skirt.
After stretching it.
First of all.
It looks like a long straight skirt now.
Then we apply elasticity to its side.
Here.
We set the elasticity ratio to be a little smaller.
60%.
It will automatically collect it.
It's a pleated skirt.
Isn't it amazing?
In the process.
You may be able to rotate the board or something.
There's a loop.
There's blood on the bottom left corner of the screen.
And then.
The particle diameter is reduced a little bit.
Otherwise.
The shape of its pleats will be more hard.
Okay.
After adjustment.
We're going to go ahead.
You can modify its physical properties.
Now its pleats are relatively small.
So we can put it.
Elasticity.
Strength.
And then we'll see.
There will be a lot of details along the line.
The pleats appear.
Of course.
If you think the pleats are a little too deep.
You can give it a little bit.
There's another way.
Make the pleats look more obvious.
You can reduce the bend intensity a little bit.
When the bend intensity is reduced.
The pleats will look thinner overall.
What do you have to pay attention to in the 2D cartoon?
I think.
In fact.
You can do it the same way.
It's not much different.
No matter what model you use.
It's the same.
The main thing is to refer to its thickness.
And its
That's what we're going to do.
If you think it's too long.
You can make the skirt tighter through this proportion.
If the skirt is tighter on the side.
It's going to look more like this.
Understand?
So this skirt.
It's going to look like this.
I think I just saw a mistake in the middle of the editing.
Okay.
Then we'll combine the front and the back.
That's it.
Finally, combine the belt here.
Okay.
Then you can see.
If we activate the belt.
Because you added the elasticity on the side.
To shrink this fold.
So the belt is here.
If you activate the simulation.
It will be dragged away by this elasticity.
Drag away.
After that.
There's a sharp corner.
Right?
Now if there are problems like this.
We need to change the fabric attribute to this belt.
Because now the belt.
It's to the same property as the body.
That's his property.
It is relatively soft.
He will be thin.
Omega.
For example, the flexibility of this place.
Pull this point over here.
It doesn't look good.
So we're going to copy a fabric.
Copy a fabric.
Ma constancy of one or two beats.
pasted on the belt.
Here.
We are.
Let's change the type to Trim Fusible Rigid
This attribute is a very hard fabric
You can see that its gold-plated strength is 70
After changing this fabric, we need to tighten the belt a little bit
Okay, it won't deform due to external factors
Do you understand?
So if you want the belt to not deform
It's pretty and flat
Just use the Fusible Rigid fabric attribute, understand?
Finally, you can increase or decrease the strength of the belt
Okay, let's learn another one
I want to see what this is for
Oh, this is also to make a skirt that looks like a puller
Yes, the skirt that we pull
In addition to the skirt that looks like a puller, there is also a skirt that looks like a puller, right?
In addition to the straight puller in the vertical direction, there is also a kind of oblique puller
What about the oblique puller?
Here we first cut a layer of the dragon
After cutting a layer of the dragon, we need to adjust its line of the powder
Let me show you the final simulation effect
Here is this skirt
This is an oblique puller
What I just did was this skirt
Now we are going to look at this skirt
Okay, let's cut a layer of the dragon
Because it must be the front
There must be two plates
It can only cross
So let's cut a plate of the dragon first
This way, you can quickly arrange it automatically in the 3D window
Then we sew the side again
First of all, the left side is used to fix it
So the left side is sewn all the way
Then the Fusible Rigid type has to be changed to TURN
Because they are folded together
Then on the right side, we just need to do this
Just sew the whole side on a small section
Then freeze the plates that will be affected
Take a look
After all are frozen
Open the simulation
It will automatically form an oblique fold
Understand?
In fact, it is to use the length and length of the Fusible Rigid
Then simulate the plate inside the activation
Okay
After simulation
Reduce the粒子間距
Reduce the thickness of the fold
These are all common operations
This is the oblique fold
After that
Let's take a look
This section
If you want it to be tighter
You just move it up a little bit
So it will be tighter
The fold will be more obvious
So is this very simple?
You just need to cut a layer of the dragon
Then modify the sewing line
That's it
So making a skirt
In fact, it's not as difficult as you think
But you must pay attention to the process
See if the sewing line is wrong
Like me
I put it on the other side
I also used the same method to change
But it closed
Right?
The reason is because
Now this is our outer plate
It's sewn here
Then here
If you sew here
The bottom is blank
There is no sewing line
It's weird
It's just left in the air
So we have to go back
Check if there is any problem with the sewing line
There is a difference in the type of sewing line
Turned sewing line
It's a stack of sewn plates
For example, this side is sewn on the same side
And these two plates
Is it covered?
In the end, this plate will be covered on this plate
Then this side of the sewing line
It's going to be turned
It will put this side
To flatten
There will be no protrusion
It's like a shawl
Flatten it
But if it's the same
They are in the same level relationship
For example, these two are both inner plates
Then here you just use
Custom Angle
Okay
Next we are going to modify the sewing line
Because it just shrunk
Let's take a look here
Let's check this plate carefully
In fact, you can see
When you look at the sewing line
There is no sewing line in this section
So it is now
It's left in the air
Then this plate
Because it is sewn together with this plate
This back piece is sewn together with it
Then this section
We will finally tighten it here
So actually you look from the outside
This side should be sewn on the outside
So we have to modify the sewing line
it is good
Then we have to put the side
We have to delete all the sewing lines on the side
So everyone in the process of creating a sewing line
Remember that it is best not to sew cross-layer
We will delete these sewing lines first
Then we will re-create the sewing line
It's okay to sew these two sides together
It's fixed
It won't shrink up
Then the inner plate here is ok
It's normal
Okay, let's modify it
After the sewing line type
We're going to check it out
Is there a mistake in the position of your fold
Then simply drag the plate
Let it be symmetrical as much as possible
And if there is an inner layer
Reduce the particle diameter
Then here we can see
Its sewing line type is custom angle
We're going to change it to turn
If you modify it again, it will be in a flat state
Otherwise it will always look like
It's like there's an air bubble up there
In fact, this is the property of turn
Everyone just remember
When you fold it, you must change it to turn
Otherwise it will stick out
It doesn't look good
Okay
Then we'll make the bottom a little longer
Okay, next
What we're going to learn is to make a fish tail skirt
What about the fish tail skirt
We're actually very simple
First of all, the fish tail skirt
You have to put this upper body first
The position of the long barrel
Do it well
After doing it, make one that is equal to it
And then the length is the same
Then the length is almost
The rectangle that you confirm the length
Then you have to copy and paste
And copy the pattern of duron
Anyway, these are all very simple operations
Put it on the back
Then arrange the front
After arranging
We sew them together
Use a threading tool to sew them together
Okay, after sewing it up
Now we are going to make the fish tail.
Let me show you the final effect of this fish tail skirt.
This is the fish tail skirt we made.
As you can see, the structure of the fish tail skirt is that its upper body is a straight skirt,
and its lower body is like an umbrella skirt.
Okay, let's continue.
Now we are going to make the umbrella skirt.
For the umbrella skirt, we are going to use the extension tool,
and then we are going to open the sheet.
Because now the sheet is straight, it is a rectangular shape,
it is not wrinkled.
But if we open it along the middle,
it will become a fish tail.
It has some waves and some wrinkles.
This is how to make a fish tail skirt.
We are going to make a fish tail skirt.
Separate it.
The upper body is a straight skirt,
so we are not going to move it.
We just need to move the rectangular sheet of the lower body.
Do you understand?
Okay, then after we are done,
we will point the straight line above.
Because after you spread it,
you need to know why I use it to spread it directly,
instead of stretching the side of this sheet.
It is because of this sheet,
after we spread it,
this side is still equal to it.
Because this is the starting point of our spread.
We are extending it downwards.
So since the length here is the opposite,
then it will not have a strange spine along this side.
This is also convenient for us to join the top points later.
There are some other operations.
Do you understand?
If you think this width is not enough,
we can tighten it up here.
And then if you tighten the knee here,
you have to tighten the bottom here a little bit.
Tighten it with the length change.
Okay, because I have a lot of content to talk about today.
I'm afraid everyone will be sleepy later.
After we tighten it,
the fish tail will become more and more obvious.
If you think it is not enough,
you can open it again.
You can make it a little more exaggerated.
After making it a little more exaggerated,
we have to pay attention.
Do you see that there are two folds here?
Right?
Okay, these two folds,
in fact, sometimes they do not look very beautiful.
Because usually when you wear a skirt,
you will not have these very rough folds.
Then we can find out through observation
if this fold is extended from here.
Right?
Then why is this one extended?
It's because our point,
this place,
it is a very rough corner.
Then you sew it together with this point,
this part will move down,
because in order to balance it.
Wait a minute,
I don't know why I keep hearing that cctalk in the background.
Someone is calling me.
Okay, so here,
we are going to make it into a smoother curve,
so that it won't hang on top,
and form this path.
There will be a recording,
and if you don't understand it now,
there will be a detailed version later.
You can also take a look at that,
and then choose this point,
and convert it to a free curve point.
After converting it to a free curve point,
we have to adjust the circle.
For example,
this section may be a little boring,
because it's a little boring.
I'm just teaching you how to change the board.
In the process of moving the curve point,
everyone should remember that
this curve point must be changed into a smoother curve.
And these two corners,
try to make sure it is a straight corner.
Do you understand?
Try to make sure it is a straight corner.
Why?
Let's go back to before.
You can see that
our previous curve is like this.
When the curve was like this before,
this corner is a sharp point.
It is a Cologne symmetrical board.
So if you look closely at the 3D window,
you will see that
the straight corner is flat.
In our software,
it is not suitable to make some hard surfaces.
If you have to make a hard surface metal material,
then you can adjust the strength of the gold veneer,
the angle line,
and the curve strength to 99.
In this way,
the board will not deform.
Then you can see that
this place,
because we have a sharp corner now,
there is a hollow place in the middle.
After you sew it up,
the sharp corner
will hang on the board.
Then it will not be flat.
So we must adjust it to a straight corner.
After adjusting it to a straight corner,
this place is flat.
Then it looks like there is no wrinkle.
Do you understand?
The A-shaped part is over.
Are you a fake fan?
Next,
we will make a cake skirt.
The cake skirt is very simple.
The cake skirt is super simple.
It is a rectangular board.
Then sew it up.
Use thread to sew it up.
After sewing it up,
arrange the board at the side point.
Then you must pay attention to
adjust the diameter a little higher.
This way,
it will not be different from the body.
I also think it is very close.
Then reduce the diameter of the particle diameter to 10.
Reduce the thickness of the collision to 1.
This way, it is more soft to simulate.
I am MD's official Xueli.
After we have simulated it,
the cake skirt has a multi-layered structure.
The cake skirt has a multi-layered structure.
Right?
So we have to make it
on the base of this layer.
OK.
Do we have a lot of creases here?
When we make a cake skirt,
do you find that
if we make a cake skirt
and other panels,
if there are a lot of creases here,
if you want to add another layer
on this layer,
it will be unstable.
I don't know if you have encountered it.
If you have encountered such a situation,
when making such a skirt,
we have a little trick.
And this little trick
is that you can use it
no matter what kind of multi-layer structure you are making.
You can add a shrink.
Let it become a very tight structure
and then a structure
with no creases at all.
How to add a shrink?
When adding a shrink,
you must be clear.
Because our panels are all gold and emerald.
So use this tool first.
After you select a panel,
you will see a arrow.
This arrow is the direction of our gold emerald.
This arrow is parallel to
our gold emerald.
And the 90-degree angle
is the direction of the emerald.
Do you know that
if I want this panel
to shrink into a very flat
panel,
we want it to shrink
to shrink
Naughty.
Although this panel is swelled
with a lot of paper,
or the bend angle
can also be adjusted
to make the fiber
of a lot of planitia
sagging like crabs.
Then copy and paste a layer to activate, and re-arrange this version.
When you re-arrange it, you must remember to check it during the arrangement process.
Like me, I didn't notice that it crossed behind, and I had to re-arrange it again.
After re-arranging it, you can see that the shape of the phoenix is now turned into a turntable, because they are stacked together.
At this time, because of the outer layer, I changed its tail pixel rate to 100.
It is now very stable, and there is no problem with the position of the belt.
It is very stable, and there is no problem with the position of the belt.
In this case, we are now relatively stable overall.
We slowly change the inner layer tail pixel rate from 30 to 60, and then change it back to 180 little by little, and then add it up to 100.
In this way, we can prevent a lot of instability in the simulation process.
Have you learned it?
Learn to type 1.
We can avoid a lot of trouble when making كلگити tour models
Using this method, we can avoid a lot of trouble in the simulation process, especially when doing this multi-layer structure.
Some problems will arise whether the fabric of the table is design, or else the elastic feeling of the cut.
Beautiful bra重要
There are many fitting types of citation pattern could be used
Very simple freedom quieres
Very simple freedom wishes
You know, it can't hold it anymore, and there will still be a problem with the freeze, because the freeze is still there, and there will still be a problem with the bump, understand?
Okay, so can anyone tell me, like this belt, if it is deformed by other plates, what should we do?
I mentioned it before.
That's right, it's a hard material, so we're going to copy it to a layer, and then we're going to use it on the belt.
If it's hard, it can't be maintained very well.
Because, yes, so in order to prevent the difference, the best thing is to change it to something else.
It's okay to stick it together.
In fact, it's okay to stick it together.
Fusible Rigid is a kind of tape.
But our software now, because of the past version of the tape, after you add the tape, I will answer one by one.
First of all, I will answer the tape.
For the tape, in the previous version, we automatically used Fusible Rigid for the tape.
That's okay.
But in the new version, it's changed.
It's changed to, if you use tape, it's better to use the softer tape.
For the tape, it's not that hard.
It will still deform.
So we usually just change it to a Fusible Rigid fabric.
Then I will answer the friction force.
The friction force is not that good.
It will still deform in the skirt version, especially when it is super large and super long.
Then do it.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
After doing the outer layer, the inner layer will be restored to the outer top.
That's right, that's right.
Very smart.
That's it.
Do the inner layer first.
Put it on a little bit.
Then the skirt is directly divided into different layers.
It's like this.
I want to explain it to you.
It's here in the fold.
We will see the fold here.
It has a lot of stacked parts, doesn't it?
Then if I have a flat version at this time.
I will use this flat version to insert this fold.
Will it touch the inner and outer layers of this fold?
It's not just one touch.
It's been in contact for many, many times.
Just imagine if I take a sheet and insert it horizontally like this.
Will it touch this?
The outer layer of the inner layer will also touch.
Then the inner layer will also touch.
The outer layer will also touch.
The inner layer will also touch.
It will touch like this.
When you insert it in this way, if you use layers,
Because the layers can only identify the front of the fabric.
Although it is intelligent, it is not so intelligent.
So it will identify the mistake.
It will say.
It's like you gave an order to a thing to go to the room.
Then it keeps its foot in the room.
Then it keeps its foot outside the room.
It put its left foot in first.
Its right foot is outside.
Then it puts its right foot in.
Its left foot is outside.
Then it keeps its foot in.
It keeps its foot in.
It doesn't know if its left foot is in or its right foot is in.
So what we have to do is very simple.
Just pull both of its legs out first.
Then flatten the sheet.
Then let it go in now.
OK.
No problem.
Understand?
So you have to.
The best way is to add a shrink to the inner layer.
Anyway, it won't take much time.
Right?
OK.
Then let's see how to change its material properties.
Now we can see that the whole version of this version looks a little bumpy.
So we will reduce the curve intensity.
Yes.
So the easiest way to deal with this multi-layer structure is to make the inner layer flat first.
Why did I jump over it just now?
Anyway, if you reduce the curve intensity, it can effectively let the skirt be in this position.
For example, it is lying here now.
If you reduce the curve intensity, it can stick to the body.
We will have it later.
Everyone, you must listen to this live broadcast.
Because there is a lot of content in this live broadcast.
Here is to show you.
If you want to add its posture to this flat version,
it is very similar to pull this flat version little by little.
Don't pull too much at a time.
Because if you pull too much at a time,
let me show you.
Here, for example, I pulled so much at a time.
It will fight in the back.
Because its flat version is interspersed.
But because I am more familiar with it,
I probably know how much is a degree.
But for people who are not familiar with it,
you just adjust it a little bit at a time.
Right?
OK.
Next, I want to see what I am doing here.
What I am doing should be a
flat version.
I don't know what time I will talk about the live broadcast.
It may be five o'clock.
Because there are a lot of things.
Hello, hello, can you hear me?
Hello, hello.
I don't know if I accidentally pressed any keys.
Oh, OK.
OK.
We are going to make a flat version now.
The flat version is like this.
The structure of the flat version is like this.
Let me show you what the flat version looks like.
The flat version is like this.
This is the cake roll.
Next, we are going to make the flat version.
The structure of the flat version is like this.
We can see that there is no wrinkle along the line.
Its wrinkle is usually some wrinkle from the hammer.
OK.
So the flat version is very simple.
Why is there no wrinkle on its waist?
In fact, it is called...
It is actually called a flat version, not a Z-shaped one.
A Z-shaped one does not have this wrinkle.
When we are making a flat version,
we will make a circle first.
This circle is like this.
We first choose a border.
Then in the model editor,
you can see this border.
It is the symmetrical total length.
For example, if this total length is 470,
your circle will be entered as 470.
Then select the right arrow of the panel line.
Then expand the panel line.
The expansion of the panel line,
you must not forget to select the extension of the panel line in the process.
Then the border entered here is the total length of this skirt.
There is a foldable skirt.
The foldable skirt is behind.
The foldable skirt is at the end.
Then we must remember to select the extension of the panel line.
Otherwise, there will be no panel line in the middle.
Double click on the panel line.
You can select the entire panel line.
Then select the transition to the hole.
After the transition to the hole,
now we have a big cake.
Then we sew this big cake to the body.
No.
We sew it to the belt,
not to the body.
We sew it to the belt.
Then adjust it in the 2D window.
Okay.
Then open the simulation.
It's a loose skirt.
Well.
The bow and the pleated skirt are the last.
There will be later.
This is a loose skirt.
The loose skirt is actually very simple.
The loose skirt,
you just have to pay attention to the waist here
and the waist here.
Just match it.
OK.
Well, other content,
other questions,
you can ask in the group.
Because there is a lot of content today.
If you explain it now,
it may be a little long.
Well, if you make a loose skirt,
if you want to increase its length,
because the loose skirt is like this.
The loose skirt is a ring.
If you want to increase its length,
you actually choose the entire ring.
Extend the panel line to make it a larger ring.
Its length will change.
Well.
The lower left corner has our,
well, no.
The lower left corner has a Q-tip.
You can add a Q-tip.
Then the loose skirt.
Sometimes if we want to make it more powerful,
because the loose skirt is not the same as an ordinary skirt.
Well.
Let me show you.
This is a loose skirt.
Well.
As for the loose skirt,
we can see.
Well.
Its fabric direction is actually like this everywhere.
Its fabric direction.
For example,
we adjust it like this to be vertical.
It is vertical everywhere.
But if you are in this window now,
you click on it.
For example,
I click on this position.
Its direction is actually written.
Do you understand?
It's because it's a ring.
It's everywhere.
Its direction is uncontrollable.
Yes.
So,
because it's a circle.
its gold tail is not so easy to control.
So,
when we are adjusting the fabric properties,
we must remember.
If this is a circle-shaped plate,
its gold tail,
the strength of the sand,
and the strength of the corner line are all the same.
Because you can't tell which direction it is.
So,
you can set them to the same number.
Do you understand?
There is one more thing.
Here you can see that I used pressure.
Well.
I will click on the triangle on the left side of the pressure.
And then enter the number of small points here.
Because this way,
we can add some very, very slight pressure to it.
After adding,
you can see that this skirt will be like,
it's like it's floating.
It's a little bit more obvious than before.
Do you understand?
This is the advantage of the pressure after adding a few points.
So that it won't fly away at once.
But it can also stay in 3D space.
In 3D space.
Because its strength is balanced.
If you want to adjust the curve here,
in my video,
you must ensure that the curve of its gold tail is the same.
Do you understand?
Because it is a circle.
It doesn't,
it doesn't have the distinction of level and value.
No.
The previous version can also be small points.
And then if you want to,
if you want to make it bigger,
just like this.
Just make the whole board wider.
Wait a minute.
This is because it's a little too fast.
Yes.
If you want to make it more wrinkled,
one is that you can enlarge this circle.
Put a whole circle out.
And then put this board out a little bit.
The board is slightly expanded.
That's it.
Okay.
It's actually very simple.
Basically, there's nothing to talk about.
You can watch the video after watching it.
If there is any instability,
you must remember to first deal with the unstable place.
Okay.
Next is to make a pumpkin skirt.
Pumpkin skirt.
We used the rectangular board we made before.
Then I stole a lazy one here.
I used the previous linear board.
You can just draw a rectangular one.
After drawing,
add a elastic here.
It will become the bottom plate of the pumpkin skirt.
And then you make this vertical set smaller.
It's a more obvious pumpkin skirt.
Pumpkin skirts are usually flat.
So we will also give it a pressure.
If you directly adjust the pressure to 2,
it may be too obvious.
It's too much.
If that's the case,
we can click on the pressure on the left.
Set its vertical to a small point.
Small point.
For example, this is 0.5.
You count 0.5.
It's not that flat.
Because if you add too much pressure,
it will fly up.
Another point is that everyone must pay attention to
why I can use that pressure here.
It's because the loose skirt in front of it
is because its weight can be balanced.
And this skirt,
because it's all collected,
there is a elasticity at the bottom.
So it won't fly up.
If you make clothes directly,
a board,
don't put too much pressure on it.
You must pay attention.
The force must be balanced.
Do you understand?
Okay.
Then this skirt,
for example, if I release the elasticity now,
because I don't use a lot of pressure,
so it's still balanced now.
It won't fly up the skirt.
Then why did I delete the elasticity
here?
It's because you can see
if I use the elasticity here,
in the software,
if you have a place to lose weight,
lose a lot of weight,
or you can reduce the size of this board to a very small extent,
because the elasticity here,
you can see that it is 40%.
Its length is about this much.
It's even possible that it's this long.
After it is tightened,
because the overall size of this area will become smaller,
so it will automatically go to some smaller places,
such as the knee,
or it will slowly move down.
This is why everyone is usually doing clothes.
Have you found that
when you do a belt or other structure,
for example,
you put it under your chest,
but it will slide down a little bit.
In fact, it is not a slide,
but its strength is too great.
It's too tight here.
Just like you wear clothes,
you can't let it stuck under your chest.
It will hurt.
You will move it a little bit to your waist.
This is why everyone
may encounter you in the process of doing it.
Why is my belt moving randomly?
Why is my belt moving
when it is under my chest?
Because its size is not enough.
As long as its size is in line with the human body,
it will not fall down.
If you have a dorsal line,
if there is still a problem,
we can see how to fix it later.
Here,
because you added elasticity,
we can't let it stuck under the leg.
Yes,
so now we have to use a side
to fix the lower part.
So what we need to do next
is to move them away first,
and then draw a rectangle.
Okay,
after drawing a rectangle,
press Ctrl D,
put it in place,
select these two panels,
arrange them,
and then sew the sides together.
Okay,
and then here,
yes, you can,
oh,
if the skirt always slides down,
one is because the skirt panel is too big,
forget to change the panel,
and the other is your waist.
The waist is not in the right size.
And then here,
I chose to make a belt.
I will fix this belt on the leg at the end,
so that the skirt will not slide down
or move randomly.
And then here,
we will see,
there used to be children who would ask,
why is there only two lines here?
Why do others have many lines?
So,
it's because your grid is too small.
If you switch to the normal grid display here,
you will see that there are only two grids here.
And then,
the sewing line,
it goes according to the top of the grid.
So, there are only two grid tops here.
There are only two lines,
understand?
So, what we have to do is,
if you think it's weird,
and you are afraid that,
this panel is relatively small,
you can directly reduce the particle diameter.
So, here,
we choose these two panels.
And then,
it's still the same operation.
if you directly touch it,
this panel will fall down,
because it's a bit big.
I will add two fixing pins.
After adding two fixing pins,
use the sewing machine to sew it up.
Okay.
First, use the sewing machine
to fix this belt on the leg.
After fixing it,
you will find that
the width is a bit too wide.
It's loose.
Let's adjust it again.
After sewing,
because there is a sewing needle,
it won't move.
And sometimes,
when you change some movements,
and when you do some movements
with a larger width,
if you don't add the sewing needle,
this side,
because it may be a bit narrow,
it will move randomly.
So, here,
we just use the sewing needle
to fix it.
Understand?
This side,
will be used to control
the bottom of the pumpkin skirt.
You can set its transparency to 0
according to your needs,
so that you can't see this side.
And the friction coefficient will be increased.
After increasing the friction coefficient of this side,
it will be relatively
difficult
to move because of external forces.
When the friction coefficient is particularly high,
this panel will be hung on the model.
Basically, it won't move.
But unless you have a big force outside,
you can't pull it out.
Otherwise,
it will usually stick to the skin.
Okay,
then freeze these two panels.
This tie is done.
After the tie is done,
you can see that
when this skirt is naturally down,
it should be near this position,
right?
Right?
Then I will put the tie
on the top first.
In this way,
the fabric in the vertical direction
is also more.
Finally,
I can make a more beautiful pumpkin skirt.
And you can sew it according to the needs.
Use the sewing machine
to sew here.
Okay,
after sewing,
I can simulate it.
And finally,
it looks like a pumpkin.
I sewed this side
to show you
the other side
when I sewed this side.
This side.
If you don't see this side,
you can sew this side.
In this way,
this side
is hidden in the skirt.
From the outside view,
you can see
that this side
will be hidden
in the skirt.
If you look from the outside, it's only here, do you understand?
And you can also make this tie a little higher, and it will look more obvious when it looks like a pumpkin.
Because pumpkins are like this, it's not what we did before, it's a curve like this.
But if you put it here now, it will look like it's hooked in.
Do you understand?
This is a pumpkin.
So we're going to use a tie to get it.
And then you can use a transparency of 0 at the end of this tie.
So that it has a limit, and we can't see it from the visual point of view.
Do you understand?
This is a little trick.
OK.
What's the next dress?
The next one should be a uniform dress.
I was impressed by the uniform dress.
OK.
That's the uniform dress.
We're finally at the uniform dress.
First, we copy and paste a piece of paper.
After copying and pasting a piece of paper, you will see that when you change it, the grid will be penetrated.
After we select this piece of paper, we right-click and select the position to rearrange the 2D arrangement.
Rearrange the 2D arrangement.
After the arrangement, I'm going to start telling you the principle of the fold.
When we do this kind of fold,
Do you want to go to the bathroom?
Wow, my mom just made me a cup of coffee.
It's so bitter.
It's okay.
Here.
Yes, you can go to the bathroom with your phone.
No.
I've always been humorous.
OK.
Well, first of all, let's learn about this.
Okay.
Now let's learn how to do the fold.
There is a recording.
And there will be a detailed explanation version later.
You can watch any version.
OK.
First of all, let's take a look.
For the fold version that we will fold at the end.
In fact, it is not such a complete version.
It has to have three such versions.
Why?
Let's take a look at the principle of the fold.
First of all, I will draw two internal lines first.
These two internal lines are used to fold.
After using the fold,
Choose one of the lines.
Let's set its fold angle to 0.
Take a look.
Add a fixed pin first.
Otherwise it will fall down.
OK.
After we add this fold angle.
For example, when the fold angle is 0.
This line will protrude from the front of the board to the outside.
Then let this board fold up.
If you can't see the front and back of the board when you look at it.
If you see that the two sides are the same.
That's because you opened the thick texture surface.
Here we can switch to the texture surface.
So you can see the front and back.
The front is colored.
Generally speaking, it is white.
The back is black.
When the fold angle is 0.
It will face the front.
When the fold angle is 180.
It is a flat line.
When the fold angle is 360.
It will go in.
Under normal circumstances.
If we are directly in the 3D space.
When it is in the shape of a hammer.
It doesn't have any particularly obvious fold marks.
But if we are going to print this board.
When we print a board.
It will become very hard.
The application of the fold angle will be more obvious.
So when we are in this position.
If I print it.
It will fold up very quickly.
Because I added a fixed pin on the top.
So it didn't fold up.
In fact, we can see at the bottom.
It can be very obvious.
It will fold up like a Z.
After folding up.
Did you find out?
If we want to make such a uniform fold.
It used to be three times wider.
But after you fold it up.
After it is folded.
Only one-third of it.
Only this small piece of width.
So when we are making a uniform.
We need to make a whole board.
At least it needs to be three times wider.
Do you understand?
Because it will fold up.
Okay.
So what we are going to do next.
Is to spread this board.
Spread three boards.
Okay.
Rearrange the position of 2D.
Delete the extra.
The inner line.
Okay.
Then copy and paste.
Copy and paste.
A total of three boards.
So that it is enough.
Do you understand?
Then we are going to merge the inner line.
Then merge the inner line.
And delete these extra points.
We can't keep these points.
Must delete.
Because it will be said later.
Then select these two lines.
Then select the inner line according to the curve.
Expand the number.
Select 3 times minus 1.
Because.
You can take a look.
For example, I have an expansion here.
The number is 2.
Is 3 minus 1.
3 times minus 1.
It must be like this.
Must be like this.
To be able to accurately divide it into three points.
Understand?
This is a math question.
The number of points is minus 1.
So if you want to divide it into 21 points.
That's 20 roots.
Then click OK.
After clicking OK.
We must choose to add points to the outer line of the board.
If you don't choose.
Because later we will use the function of the divider.
If you go directly to the divider.
It is a three-group recognition line.
If you don't align it to the outer line of the board.
Too difficult.
3 times minus 1.
Just remember that it is 3 times minus 1.
That's it.
Ok.
If you use the divider tool.
During the process of divider.
It is to recognize three lines as a group.
If you don't break the outer line of the board.
This line above.
There is a complete line below this line.
It can't be identified.
It will be identified on other lines.
It's wrong.
So here we are going to use the divider tool.
Select these inner lines.
Then choose to add points to the outer line of the board.
After choosing.
It will be broken.
Understand?
Do you understand?
Let me see if you don't understand.
That's why we have to break points here.
It's for a moment.
We're going to use the function of the divider.
Be sure to break points.
If you don't break points.
It can't be identified.
OK.
Next, we're going to use the function of the divider.
When using the function of the divider.
We have to find the left side of the first inner line.
We're going to record it.
Then go to the right side of the last inner line.
Double end.
Because double is in our software.
It's a definite instruction.
When drawing the inner line.
It's also a double end.
I saw the name of the fake old melon.
I can't control it.
Smile.
OK.
Then here we flip the paper.
When you open the window.
You'll see there are three options here.
This is the order.
You can see it's one six.
It's a uniform group.
It's usually in order.
We'll talk about it later.
All right.
In order.
Then you'll see.
This is the inner line of each fold.
Choose three.
Be sure to choose three.
Because we are a group of three.
Okay.
Then click OK.
When we're done.
We'll see it here.
It will automatically give you.
It's a good setting.
These inner lines.
Folding angle.
OK.
Do you understand?
All right.
Hello?
Could you hear me?
And then this line.
It's a dark red color.
The big red is 0 degrees.
And the green is 360 degrees.
And the nine red is 180 degrees.
After it's automatically folded.
What are we going to do next?
Do you know?
Do you have any children?
Tell me what to do next.
We've used it now.
After folding.
Are we going to start to sew?
Ah, I think it's green.
Is it blue?
Then it's blue and green.
After we set the folding angle, do we have to sew it?
That's right.
Those of you who have read our previous videos,
we can't sew it directly.
If you sew it directly,
at the same time, it has to calculate the fold first,
and then we have to do the sewing line.
Let's take a look.
It will be unstable and wobble.
That's right.
So we have to harden the board first.
Because hardening can make it fold quickly.
Let's fold it first,
and then sew it up.
Understand?
Okay.
Fold it and sew it up.
Put it aside.
Hmm.
Okay.
Then,
here I choose to
copy and paste,
or copy and glue,
or copy and paste.
Can you tell me?
I have created the board on one side.
On the other side,
did I copy and paste it,
or copy and paste it,
or copy and paste it?
No.
I have created the board on the other side.
You have created the board on only one side.
I've created the board on the other side.
If you want to buy the board,
you can buy one.
Can you tell me who the person who answered the dragon
is?
Wrong answer!
It's neither the mirror nor the dragon.
You all answered it wrong.
It's copy and paste.
Good.
The kid answered correctly
Can only copy and paste
Can not copy and paste
Because the uniform is smooth
It's from here
If it's from the left
It's in the direction of the vertical axis
It will always be a fold in the direction of the vertical axis
Yes, it's not a whole circle
If you use
Fold, fold, axis, symmetry
And what's that
It's all wrong
This is a copy and paste
And then we're going to use the fold and fold
Just sew it over
Because if you're a mirror
One is a fold in the vertical axis
It's symmetrical
It's not one-sided
Understand?
And then sew the front and back
And then I'm going to model it
The hardening here is to fold quickly
And then the hardening is done
Okay, that's one-sided
Well, well
well
And then it's like this
That's what we can see with this dress
It's an old problem
You look at it in the front
Oh, it seems to be very flat
But in the back, it's all spread out
This is just a kid asking
Say this
Um, teacher Siqin Xiaochun
Recently, uh, making dresses
Oh, teacher Siqin Xiao Li
Uh, when I was making dresses recently
This dress is not spread out
Then the fold
All gone
Yeah, he said
The fold is flat
It's all spread out
Why?
Because of our butt here
This plate is flat
The total width of this plate is just that
And then the butt is a little full here
It will stretch this fold
So when you encounter such a situation
We usually say that this plate
It may be made three times wider
It's going to be a little bit more
So if you want to modify this plate
You have to delete these lines
So sometimes I'm lazy
I'll just do it again
Because it's going to be faster to do it again
Just make it a little bit wider
You know
Yeah
It's an out-of-the-way
And then align it to the outside of the board
As long as you force yourself to practice more
You'll get used to it
Then sew it up
Hey, I almost accidentally sewed it up
I'm going to have to make a hard decision first
Ha ha
Sometimes it takes a long time to sew it up
It takes a long time to sew it up
Wow, the deformation rate is also possible
You can directly change the deformation rate if you are lazy
I'll sew it up
Sometimes people say
Hey, why is there a black triangle?
It's okay
Just reduce the particle diameter
It's generally a particle diameter problem
The next step is to copy a plate
Then we'll look at it
Don't forget to copy a plate here
Then the finish of this plate is going to be changed
The next step is to copy a plate here
to increase the strength of the gold and silver gauze, and to increase the strength of the foot line, so that it is not easy to stretch, so that it is still a flat and neat board.
Ah, yes, if there is a small black triangle, then reduce the粒子間距
Is the fold not hard enough?
Ah, you still have to fold more, you have to fold more, you just put the board, if you are lazy, just think about it,
If you are not lazy, just widen the board a little bit, and count again.
Don't just drag the board, here you can only change the shrink or redo it again.
Because if you just drag the board, the fold, the fold board, then it is like this, the grid is interspersed.
If you go to change the grid, to extend the grid, then all the grids will be in the same position, and then it will start to intersperse.
It is very troublesome for you to modify it again, it is better to redo it again.
OK.
Then here we will see that it still has some, this skin still has some spread.
Then we can reduce its playability a little bit, so that it looks a little more flat.
There is one more thing, let's reduce the粒子間距 a little bit more.
You can see that it may be very obvious that there will be some folds in this place, especially in this place, see?
This, this kind of fold is because this board is now a little more than three times.
OK.
So when we sew, there will be some folds here.
If you want to smooth out this fold, you can change a property called the deformation rate.
The deformation rate, wait a minute.
What am I doing here?
I seem to be checking what happened, and then I will increase the deformation rate to 100, and the folds will be gone.
That is the value of the deformation rate.
As long as you remember.
Remember 0, 80 and 100.
Don't adjust the other values.
It's okay if you want to adjust it, but it's not necessary.
Understand?
When it's 100, the function of the deformation rate is to say, simply put, is it easy for the board to be deformed by external forces?
If it's 100, it's especially easy to be deformed, especially the fold line.
Understand?
Especially the fold line.
So the deformation rate, you can imagine it very simply.
Is there a fold in the position of the fold line?
If it is 100, the position of the fold line will not have a fold.
No matter which board it is, the position of the fold line will not have a fold.
When it's 100, when it's 0, all the folds will be there.
All of its properties will not be weakened.
Understand?
0.
We didn't show 0 here.
Anyway, as long as you remember 0, this board is not easy to be deformed by external forces.
This may be a little difficult to understand.
As long as you remember 100, the position of the fold line will not have a fold.
It's very flat.
Right?
Do you remember that there were so many folds just now?
The folds are gone.
It's because I changed the deformation rate to 100.
Then the fold at the bottom will still be there.
It's just that the fold at the bottom of the fold line has been flattened.
Do you understand?
If you don't understand, I can explain it again.
Okay.
Why is no one typing 1?
Yes, yes.
Now it's me.
I'm Xueli.
To make it easier for everyone to understand.
Let's take another look.
I'm going to hide this.
Mission.
Why?
Oh, I got it.
I put it like this.
Because I see a lot of missions below.
This is.
I'll show you again.
Let's talk about it again.
Okay.
80 is common.
80 is the default shape.
For example, this is a board.
Then.
Then we sew it up.
After sewing up.
Oh.
A board.
You double.
If you double it, you can just stretch it out.
After stretching it out.
Let's simulate it.
Okay.
Now we have a lot of folds at the bottom of the fold line.
The fold at the bottom of the fold line is the thinnest and the densest.
And then when it goes down little by little.
Is this fold open?
Right?
Yeah.
Then after it's unfolded.
If we put this board here.
Okay.
We set its deformation rate to.
100.
Hey.
The miracle happened.
Is the fold at the bottom still there?
Right?
And it might be more.
It's even more.
But it's all flattened here.
Understand?
This is the difference.
Obviously, their physical properties are the same.
But your deformation rate is 100.
Because the sewing line is super useful to it.
Just smooth it out.
Smooth out the folds here.
Then why are there so many folds at the bottom here?
Well, do you want to listen to this academic statement?
The academic statement is this.
That is to say.
Deformation rate.
It controls how many folds will deform.
In fact.
When the deformation rate is 0.
All the folds are there.
The sewing line position.
It has a total of 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11.
Anyway, it's almost 20 folds.
Right?
Here.
There are 20 folds here.
If your deformation rate is 100.
Then.
These 20 folds will be deformed by external forces.
What about them?
It's all from this place.
Hey.
It's down.
Well.
Okay.
That's better than me.
When I am 100% sure.
Just say.
Just.
Um.
I want to see.
I know what the academic statement of this thing is.
But.
Um.
He understands that it is a little troublesome.
When the deformation rate is 0.
It means that the folds are 0 percent incisive.
Because.
All fold properties are incisive.
Just like a paper.
After you fold it.
Whatever it does.
Back to its original smoothness.
He still has that fold in it.
At the fold position.
Just 1.
You have to be careful.
It has to be like this.
The first.
Because another way of putting it.
Oh.
There's no need to put it on.
There.
For example, when you fold the paper, the fold is sharp, but when you hold the paper, it is soft and soft, do you understand?
I will upload the live video after May 1st holiday.
I can't open the camera to show you the demonstration.
In general, once a fabric forms a fold, the properties of the fold and its properties will be different.
It's like playing a game.
So the deformation rate is how many percent of the fold will be reduced.
If it is 0, the fold of 0% will be on the B-stand.
0% of the fold will be deformed.
0% of the fold will be deformed, that is, there will be no fold deformation.
The properties of the fold will be reduced.
All the folds will remain the same.
So they will come out along this edge.
But if the deformation rate is 100%, that is, all the folds will be deformed.
Their properties will be reduced.
Their properties will be reduced by the deformation rate.
So the deformation rate is 0, right?
If the deformation rate is 0, all the folds will be 0% times 10%, 0% times 20%, 0% times 11%.
All of them will be 0, 0, 0.
All of them will be 0.
If all of them are 0, the folds on this edge will be gone.
Because its physical properties have become 0.
It has no deformation intensity.
It becomes very soft.
So it will be all down.
And this edge has no fold.
Understand?
Look, if the deformation intensity is relatively high, it will shake like this.
So everyone must pay attention when using deformation rate.
That is, if you use deformation rate, you have to adjust the deformation intensity a little bit.
Understand?
Yes, yes, yes, that's what it means.
So it can actually be written into a formula.
That is to say, the deformation rate is how many folds will deform.
And then the deformation intensity is a percentage.
You can see it when you click it.
It has a interval of 0 to 1.
Okay, I finally got this for you.
Okay, let's take a look at it next.
Everyone has definitely encountered this problem when making dresses.
If you haven't encountered it, you will meet it in the future.
That is to say, we simulate it and find it.
Hey, how did he, how did he get out of the place where he should have fallen in?
It should have gone in from outside.
How did it get inside?
Have you ever encountered such a problem?
If you have encountered this problem, please post it.
You can post it on the chat.
Well, what about such a problem?
It's very simple, not as difficult as you think, I don't know how you deal with it, there are many ways to deal with it, one is that you can redo the dress, there is also a method, it's very simple, you can use a fixed needle.
Let's go back to a more stable time, you try it first, you don't give up, you adjust it, you drag it around, if you drag it around, it's useless, it's very simple, we use this fixed needle tool, you find this edge, which should be the 0 degree edge, this edge should be outside in normal circumstances, right?
So what we are going to do now is to pull this edge out, so we create a fixed needle along this edge.
After creating a fixed needle, it should be like this.
After creating a fixed needle, you can find the fixed needle here, and you must pay attention to the fact that it is not simulated.
In fact, you don't have to understand the principle, because it is also possible to force it with a fixed needle, because I just pull it out with a fixed needle, pull this edge out, and then simulate it, and it will be stable.
You must pay attention to the fact that it is not simulated.
Pull the fixed needle out first, because the fixed needle will, yes, the jade will not break the fixed needle.
Anyway, you just pull the grid out.
You just pull the grid out.
And then finally sew it up.
Wait a minute, I pour a cup of water.
Hello, can you hear me? Hello?
Well, yes, and then we can reduce the particle diameter to 5 again.
There is a reason to reduce the particle diameter to 5.
That is, after I reduce the particle diameter to 5 here, I can delete the internal line.
Well, if you delete the internal line, it is to make it more smooth.
Just double-click one internal line, double-click again, and you can select all the internal lines on this board.
And then if you start to simulate the double-click control grid, you can, because when the particle diameter is 5, your computer will be more laggy.
Well, when the particle diameter is 5, your computer will be more laggy.
I think that when the particle diameter is 5, it is laggy, when the double-click control grid is simulated, it simulates a few needles at once.
So you can lagging that time to make this edge of the fold not dissipate.
I am alive.
I was 209, not 206.
The online course is the teaching videos I recorded, and then there are materials with accessories.
There are so many materials.
Then you have to learn little by little, okay, and then here we are double-channel simulation, so that we can do a short-term simulation, and we can just lock it in a form that has not transformed into a completely scattered form to simulate.
Okay, let's take a look. If the particle diameter is not 5, but 20 or 15, let's see what happens.
For example, the particle diameter is 15, then the overall simulation speed is very fast, right? When the simulation speed is very fast, if we delete this internal line now, after deleting it, because the number of networks is not a lot.
If you have time to send me a change of work, I can take a look, because there are not many people who buy classes now, but I won't go to work on May 1st.
May 1st, I am, wow, my voice is already mute, wait a moment.
Hello, hello, hello, hello, okay, okay, okay, I'm a fashion designer, right?
I don't go to work on May 1st, but if you have time, you can take a look.
Wow, I'm usually very introverted, okay?
Okay, let's take a look. When the particle diameter is 15, first of all, when you delete the internal line, because the grid surface is triangular, so this place is bumpy, bumpy, bumpy.
Then we usually, if you go directly to simulate, the fold will be dissipated soon.
So we can apply the fold angle to it.
After applying the fold angle, the particle diameter should be reduced to 5, then double-click to simulate, understand?
You must let your computer simulate when it is particularly stuck, it will not be easy to dissipate.
Well, if you buy a class, you can see it in our MD's official homepage.
CCTalk and CGE model online.
CCTalk and CGE model online, it was sold.
Okay, let's look at the Bureau, and Bureau is a couple of other 증 Medium.
It is different from theicedanners andcut bunny.
Let us fold it first.
For the time being, the Bureau is not people's personal idea.
In fact, you can see from the side that it is a gradual as a creative word.
That's why it is also the GE fait medo.
The sewing direction is also the same as that of Shunzhe.
Oh, thank you CG Magic Star Network, thank you baby.
You can buy it on CG Magic Star Network.
The customer service of CG Magic Star Network is super, super good.
Super, super good, really good, very enthusiastic.
Thank you baby, thank you.
Okay, after we fold it, we will see this version.
For convenience, let's adjust the color.
In fact, Gong Zi Zhe is like this.
It is a fold that is first poked and then tucked in, then poked and then tucked in.
So everyone must remember that this type is called Gong Zi Zhe.
When making some small dresses, you may use Gong Zi Zhe.
Who is Xiao Ni Bao? Why do you keep sending cute emoticons?
Okay.
After the double-click to delete all the internal lines,
it will automatically fold here.
Then we can see that after folding, it is a very neat one.
It will be poked first and then tucked in, poked and then tucked in.
This fold is called Gong Zi Zhe.
Have you learned it?
Learn to type.
In fact, the difference between it and Shunzhe is that
when we use this folding fold tool, the options are different.
It's different.
Understand?
Okay.
The last one is to tell you that there is one that is actually not a skirt,
but one that everyone will ask.
First of all, let's put a rectangular seam on the body.
What exactly is our usual skirt?
Let's take a look.
First of all, it is now equal length.
That is, it is a rectangular seam in a rectangular situation.
Then we look at it from the visual effect.
If I want it to be a skirt now,
is it because after you sew it,
there is a part missing in this place?
There is a triangle missing, right?
MMD looks very real,
it should be because it is rendered and then pasted these things.
Then if you look at it from the back,
is it also missing a small part?
Yes, the A-sized part is over.
You can wait for the looping after that.
Okay.
Then here we use the folding tool,
the folding tool,
click, click,
then select this folding line,
you can fold it to both sides,
open it,
after the folding is opened,
we will not make up one more part, right?
Then pull the scissors a little faster.
Now let's simulate it again.
Because of the folding sheet,
we have added a large triangle in the middle here.
It's actually a fan shape,
but it's added here anyway.
After adding this piece,
it will be evenly placed on the front and back,
so that it forms half a skirt.
This is the principle of what we usually do with clothes.
If you don't understand,
you can sew a rectangle first,
and then where it is missing,
you can make up one more piece.
If the triangle is missing,
you can extend it with an extension.
After extending it,
it's the same as what we did with the tail skirt before.
Now this place is converted to a curve point,
and then these two points are converted to a curve point,
and then adjust the plate.
This is the principle of making a flat skirt,
or making a side skirt.
What I'm going to do now is actually
to find a reference picture for you.
It's actually this version,
this skirt.
Because sometimes people do it,
wow,
will this be warned?
Okay,
everyone is doing that.
Well,
when you have some clothes,
you may have something like this.
It's just like this.
Hey,
hey,
this is how it goes into this kind of flowery side
and some otherwise,
that's decoration.
What about this decoration?
It's also done in this way.
You put it now,
it's wide,
it's long two days ahead,
right,
it's not wide two days ahead.
Then you make the front of this line up a little longer,
does it form such a
curl,
pull down from little by little,
So even if you don't know how to draw this version, you can also make it by modifying it little by little.
Then we adjust the curve with the editor tool.
Liu Naitang, hello, hello, Liu Naitang.
Liu Naitang seems to have won our award, right? I remember that he seems to have won our award.
Then convert this point to a curve point, and then in the middle, don't forget the corner, because we have to fight at the end.
So this corner is 90 degrees, this corner is also 90 degrees, and this corner is also 90 degrees.
Do you understand?
OK.
Then if we want to make this version fold more clearly,
we will first put this powder line back into the fire, and then select these two lines in the middle.
Right click, select the line that is created according to the curve.
We do the same as we usually do.
Fold first.
OK.
Draw the inner line first, prepare to fold.
Then here, use the folder button function.
Can you tell me which option we should choose in the folder button?
Note that the powder line here is anti-activated.
I didn't delete the powder line.
Are there any smart children who can tell us which option we should choose here?
Hmm, I have seen the correct answer.
The correct answer is 3, the one who is in love.
How can there be a second one?
What is the one who is working?
And the one who is working?
Oh, actually we are going to use the one who is in love here.
The method of the one who is in love and the other two is different.
What is the prize?
There is no prize.
No prize.
Thank you.
I can read your name.
Thank you for the answer.
Here we are going to use the one who is in love.
The one who is in love is different from the other ones.
The one who is in love is a living one.
What is a living one?
This side can be opened.
When we used the one who is in love before,
For example, when we use the one who is in love structure like this,
we will see that it will actually be sewed together here.
Its left and right sides will be sewed together here.
Okay.
E F G Y F G H J H F D.
The left and right sides will be sewn together here.
It is a fixed pleated seam on the seam side.
So the fold here is already folded.
It can't be spreaded here.
However, the one we are doing now can be opened later.
So let's use the one who is in love here to fold it.
And its sewing line is different from this one.
The sewing line here is used to sew the pleating seam.
When sewing,
But here we use free sewing machine to sew.
We fold it first, and when they are folded, we can activate the sewing line.
After the hardening is finished, we put this board nearby.
Everyone must pay attention, try to make it on the side,
not on the front or the back.
Then activate the sewing line, and then turn on the simulation.
Here we are not using the sewing line, but the sewing line.
After sewing, is it folded now?
Lin Yuan, I have a friend who knows Lin Yuan.
He is a singer for Lin Yuan.
Lin Yuan is quite cute.
Then after folding here,
we just control D, create a symmetrical one.
Then finally sew the back piece, and then sew the front piece.
You can see that we don't fold it here.
Just sew it directly.
No need to use sewing.
Understand?
Because it's not a pile.
Okay.
If we want to change the length of this skirt,
Little Nipo is so cute.
Why do you keep making expressions?
So cute.
Here we can't move this side directly.
What we have to do is,
if you want to change its length,
how do we change it?
Do you know?
If I want to change its length now,
for example, I want to make it equal to 10 centimeters,
how should I change it?
Do I move this side directly?
Wake up.
That's right.
Thin green, thin green.
Correct answer.
We are going to expand the outline.
That is to say,
if you pull this side directly now,
it may deform.
So here we use the outline expansion.
Everyone remember that it is the outline expansion.
It can be expanded to add a section.
Because it is not rectangular.
When you make this rectangular,
you may choose this side when you pull it long.
Then you pull it down, it will be long.
Right?
But its structure is a structure with a curve.
So we usually choose this side,
and then the outline expansion.
When the outline expansion,
this corner,
its angle is not along here.
It is a rectangle, right?
Because here we choose perpendicular,
which is a rectangle.
Then we want to switch to extend,
which is extension.
This is right.
One more piece comes out.
Okay, then we simulate it.
It adds a whole wide.
Then after adding it,
we select all the sides in the middle.
Right click, select align outline.
It will automatically extend to the outline.
At this time, it will be fine to simulate it again.
Then when we use the extension,
not extension,
when the outline expansion tool,
the powder line here is not right.
So we have to re-edit it.
Understand?
Okay, then finally,
it's okay to simulate it again here.
And then at the end,
you can reduce the particle diameter.
Then delete these internal lines.
I'll explain it to you again.
Okay?
It's about why this panel is using the panel extension.
It is also two shapes.
This is a rectangle.
For example, this is a rectangle.
If you want to make it longer,
you just have to pull it like this.
But if it is a multidirectional,
then you have to add it to the length.
It must be added equally wide like this.
But if you pull it directly,
its side will change.
You know, it was set up well.
It will be like this.
Its angle will be smaller and smaller.
Understand?
This angle will be smaller and smaller.
So in this case,
we have always selected this side.
Right click, expand the panel outline.
Then select extension.
This is extension.
If it is a rectangle,
it is its expanded rectangle.
Then here,
perpendicular is perpendicular.
If you select extend,
it is like this.
Along this edge.
Then there is another option,
which is mirror.
Mirror is a mirror.
Why do some people sometimes choose a mirror?
Because sometimes we have to turn this edge up and fold it.
For example, the edge of the sleeve.
Then you have to choose mirror for the edge of the sleeve.
Because in the end,
you will fold this edge and here.
You will fold it up in the middle.
Understand?
You may have an inner line in the middle.
At the end of this edge,
you will fold it up.
For the sleeve,
you may fold it in like this.
That's why we use mirror.
Understand?
Okay.
Then our video should be almost finished.
Do you have any questions
during the process of using MD?
Here are some of the things
we made.
About how to make these dresses.
Basically,
I have talked about
some of the ways to make dresses.
For rendering,
you can use other software to render.
Do you have any other questions?
Let's see.
Vray.
Yes.
There is a screen.
There is blood on the lower left corner.
The hips are bigger.
The waist is thinner.
There are a lot of wrinkles on the waist.
Did you not listen carefully?
Baozi.
In the first lesson,
we talked about
how to add a line.
How to add a line.
If you want to make an animation,
you have to delete the inner line first.
The inner line of the fold is correct.
Then,
on the right side of the board,
there is a
shape optimization.
Understand?
It's in the middle.
Okay.
Let me give you a brief explanation.
How to add a line.
What is that?
That is,
without the line.
If there is no line,
without the line,
there is a wrinkle on it.
Right?
Look,
there is a wrinkle on it.
That is because it is not long enough.
Because our hips are of the same size,
but there are a lot of wrinkles on the waist.
Right?
OK.
When there are a lot of creases here, you can add a dot here.
Why are there creases?
The reason for creases is basically due to the strength of the fabric and the length of the fabric.
As we can see from the edge sewing line, the sewing line here is already red, right?
The word red tells you that there is a big length difference.
So here we are going to make this edge,
first of all, because it is a set of sewing lines now,
we first change its sewing line to free sewing,
and sew it here first.
This way, the front will not be affected, and the front will be even.
In the back, we can see that it actually has a very large piece, right?
This is what we are going to talk about later, which is this rope.
Here and here are sewed together.
We can see that it has a very large piece.
The length difference here,
according to your mouse, there will be a negative 32 here, right?
If it is negative 32,
it means that you have to add one here,
and the width to be saved is 32.
Okay, and now if you are using the sewing line function to sew,
for example, free sewing, we sew here,
and then press the shift key from here to sew here,
it is equal to the length, 117.5 by 117.5.
Okay, after sewing, there is no creases here.
There is no creases on the waist here.
Do you understand?
Do you know?
Just dig a rope, dig a triangle.
It is actually to make the structure of the board more three-dimensional.
For example, even if I don't activate this inner line now,
anti-activate, oh, not the inner line,
just don't activate the sewing line.
Look, even if I don't have a sewing line,
is it also very three-dimensional like this?
Do you understand?
Yes, and then after adding the sewing line,
everyone should remember that the sewing line,
if you are directly added to the point of the sewing line,
basically to the widest point of the hip,
so we have to pull this point forward,
otherwise it will have creases in this place,
because it is hollow here and not strong.
Wow, I almost pressed Alt F4, Alt 4.
See?
It didn't point to the hip here,
so it has a creases here.
Because you dig this place,
it's actually like you dug a piece of board.
So you have to pull it down a little bit,
let it point to the hip,
and it's right.
This is very flat.
Do you understand?
Yes, dig a hole to make the board too narrow,
that's what it means.
Did you learn it?
So in fact,
wait a minute,
in order to pass the audit,
let me change it first,
so we sometimes do the top 1,
I change a model,
so when we do the top 1,
sometimes we will modify some,
just add an audit to it,
and if the size of the creases is even,
you can use the inner line to fold it.
For example,
when we are making clothes,
sometimes the clothes will have creases here.
Let me show you.
Why does it give so much face?
Why is there no strange creases?
Why is the creases gone again?
I was going to show you the strange creases,
OK, here it comes.
Sometimes,
for example,
when the curve here is not very smooth,
there will be a creases here,
do you see it?
This one, this one.
Sometimes,
after the creases come out,
if you want to smooth the creases here,
you have to find it here,
click it,
and then add a straight line,
after adding a straight line,
add a small line to it,
for example,
the width is 10,
and then it will be flat,
do you understand?
The princess dress is just a little longer,
that dress, right?
the creases in front of the chest will go forward,
this is what you're talking about, right?
Wait a minute,
it's like this,
if it's a little exaggerated, it's like this,
right?
What about this?
You just dig a triangle like this,
just dig it out,
if there's another one here,
you just add a straight line to it,
and then adjust it a little bit here,
do you understand?
So,
so in fact,
when we usually change it,
there are some logic that you need to have,
that is to say,
like this,
like you just said,
this collar here will protrude outward,
then our chest and the bottom are flat here,
so in fact,
it's not a whole line of modification,
because everyone is in the process of modification,
it's easy to think that,
hey,
I have a problem with this side,
then I'll change the whole side,
in fact,
it's not,
sometimes you have to change it,
in fact,
it may just be a dot,
you just dig this dot,
it's flat,
and then you just dig a little bit more,
what is the multidirectional line?
I don't understand,
what is the multidirectional line you're talking about?
Do you say it's a UV line?
UV line,
you may be,
for example,
you have many types of fabric,
one is white,
one is red,
two types of fabric,
then when you are in the UV editor,
you may,
I put it like this now,
then you may have to put it in two lines,
so that your UV drawing
doesn't have any extra parts,
or useless parts,
understand?
UDIM,
right?
Oh,
when you export it,
there will be a selection,
we have talked about it in the video before,
look at that,
the video of the Zhezhou class,
it's okay,
where is the Zhezhou class?
Wait a minute,
wait for me to find it,
it's,
anyway,
MD official attention,
click in,
there is,
Wuyi holiday,
I just think that the first day,
maybe everyone is more available to see,
so I put it at the time of vacation,
and Ada is available today,
she went to Shenzhou two days ago,
Xiong Henting,
up and down,
high and low,
behind,
start,
no,
this,
let me look for it,
is your board high and low?
For example,
for example,
it's like this,
right?
Wait a moment,
for example,
you are like this,
then you have to make it flat,
right?
Two pieces,
two pieces not always fight,
if there is a level,
then delete the level,
if there is no level,
then add the level,
just remember this sentence,
have a level to add a layer,
no layer,
no layer to remove.
No layers,
layers.
For example,
your clothes are low and high.
There is no tool here,
um,
Yuanzhou measure clothing,
find this tool,
then click,
click it,
then right-click,
is to have that edit measurement,
Edit, measure clothing, select this right button, select cut, and delete the excess version.
That's it, it's flat.
Did you learn it? You learned how to cut clothes.
This is a lazy method.
This is a flat cut.
Isn't it easy?
This can be cut diagonally, you know?
After you select this version, you can cut it diagonally like this.
After you cut it, select the right button, and then cut.
It can be cut diagonally.
Right?
Double-layer fabric, transparent skirt, what do you do with that?
That has something to do with transparent stickers, right?
Is the only flat version also made into a curve?
It's not.
You can also make it a straight line.
It's just that this cut is cut in 3D space.
Sometimes it cuts out the curve.
Generally speaking, it's not easy.
You must have a line.
Generally speaking, it's all flat.
You delete all the curve points on this side.
It's still a straight line.
It doesn't have to be a curve.
And on the contrary to what you think,
Generally speaking, we will keep a straight line.
Let me see if there are any more questions.
Well, they're all about the same.
The line here is opened like this.
If you want to make it stand out,
The line of the waist is the thinnest position you find on the waist.
Alt 4 is the transparent map.
Click a point to find the thinnest position on the waist.
And then from this point down,
There's a line here.
Right, right.
And then find the thinnest place on the waist.
Put the line to the thinnest position on the waist.
The widest position of this opening is the thinnest position on the waist.
Because you want to dig.
This is a hole you dug.
So you must have the least fabric in this direction.
That must be the thinnest.
So the biggest place of this opening is the thinnest position on the waist.
Then you use the line sewing tool to sew the two sides together.
I should have a video after this.
Teach you how to use this sewing tool.
Because many people don't have any concept of sewing tools.
There must be some children who will say.
Why don't I just change the side curve of this sewing tool?
Good question.
Why not?
Because you have to match the side curve.
If you change the side curve like this.
Let's take a look.
If your home is not a sewing tool, but a side curve.
One is the curve on the side.
You have to make it match the front and back.
Another point is that after you change this.
This is a sharp corner.
You have to change this curve.
You have to make a break here.
Then change this line to a straight corner.
Then change this point.
It's more troublesome.
It's okay to change.
But it's troublesome.
You know.
Sometimes you may have to change it like this.
Just let him have nails on the curve.
You can refer to the real clothes.
It's okay to start.
Straight line front.
High and low.
Then you are the same.
Use this to cut.
There is another place.
That is to say, save you after opening.
For example.
This dress.
We have opened a rope here.
Right?
The back is straight.
That is also a plus rope.
It's the same.
For example.
You add a rope here.
After adding a rope.
We usually do this.
That doesn't work.
Cut a piece.
After cutting a piece.
Cut and sew.
Right?
This is one more piece.
Then we will merge this side with this.
Oh.
Merge here.
Okay.
His rope will run to this place.
Then you look from above.
It is also relatively flat.
It won't be very obvious that something will come out.
This is called turning the rope.
The rope is turned to the side by you.
There is a good thing about turning to the side.
For example.
If you turn the position relatively down.
You can turn this place into a pocket.
For example.
You make a pocket here.
No one will see you.
There will be a rope in this place.
Do you know?
Do you understand?
This is called turning the rope.
But turning the rope in real life is more troublesome.
They may have more.
The amount of turning the rope.
But in our software.
You use this method anyway.
The rope should be in this position.
You turn it to the bottom of the page.
Or.
You can't see it in the pocket.
Or you can do the cutting design.
For example, you cut it here.
Cut into some patterns.
Something like this.
Like this.
Use this clever way.
So that no one can see the cutting line here.
The back of the coat.
I don't understand.
I think you add the rope.
As long as it is symmetrical.
It is symmetrical.
The coat.
Because of the coat.
It is not so close.
It is not so tight.
If you want to stick it.
You can put it in the side.
Then add a rope here.
Use both methods.
Just a little bit.
Then add a rope here.
Do you have any other questions?
Wow.
It is already 5.30.
Do you have any other questions?
I will give you the last 5 minutes.
The back of the coat.
It has to be close.
I tell you.
You may have some misunderstandings about the coat.
Clothes like the coat.
It is impossible.
The back is completely attached.
Do you buckle the buckle?
If you buckle the buckle.
You will add a belt.
After adding a belt.
It will naturally be closed.
There are more people learning the website.
It is cctalk.
But the cctalk group is not very useful.
Everyone doesn't like chatting inside.
I think you can also buy the cg model network.
Well, it's not okay.
Cg model network.
It's better.
The back has waist
It's so cute!
Who is it?
Can the animation ABC be displayed according to the selected version?
Unless you hide the version in the 3D space, it seems to be possible.
In my impression, if you hide the version and display it, it will not display the version.
But in fact, according to the normal logic, you can't do it.
Because the animation ABC follows the grid.
I tried it before. If you hide the version and display it, it will not display the hidden version of the animation ABC.
I changed the default clothes in the library. Can it be restored?
I won't broadcast it tomorrow. Why not tomorrow?
But today is also the 5th day off.
Can the CG model network members see the official fee tutorial?
I don't know. It should not be possible. I don't seem to have this cooperation with them.
Can the default clothes of the painter be restored by me?
I remember that it is not possible.
You can ask someone for a default clothes.
Or reinstall the software.
Or on the left side.
You can download it from the upper corner.
If you have any other questions, you can add our QQ group in the lower left corner.
Now the total number of people in the QQ group has been added to 3000.
So there should be a place.
You can add our group.
If you have any questions, you can ask in the group.
If you have time, I will answer.
Basically, the questions will be answered when I go to work.
If you are on vacation, you can look at the situation.
If you have any questions, you can ask in the QQ group.
That's all for today.
Can the clothes be turned over?
Turn over in the direction?
Do you say these two turn over?
Why do you want to turn over in the direction?
Yes, you can.
But I don't understand why you want to turn over.
Then your sewing line is not right.
Unless you want to turn over in the direction.
Turn over in the direction.
Ah, I know who you are.
You are Yu Bao, right?
NTDX.
Hey, hey.
I recognize you.
If you want to turn over in the direction,
you just choose this version.
Then there is a surface turn over.
It is the turn over line.
After the turn over, it is.
It is in the 2D window.
It is turned over in the left and right.
If you look at it in the 3D space, it is normal.
It's just that its front and back will turn over.
You can see it on the texture surface.
It's out of the line of hair.
There is a pocket on the left.
There is no pocket on the right.
We usually cancel this.
Cancel the connection.
End the connection.
Or there is a pocket on the left.
Yes, we usually do it anyway.
After doing it, we will end the connection.
Well.
Okay.
If there is no problem,
we will.
Today's live broadcast is almost here.
Bye bye, everyone.
Happy May 1st.
Happy New Year.
Bye bye.
Good.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye bye.
Good.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye bye.
Good.
It's holiday.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye bye.
Let's eat.
Let's play games.
Bye bye.
Goodbye, everyone.
Don't roll.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, everyone.
Bye bye.
Thanks for watching!